三傻大鬧寶萊塢
喂?
Hello?
什么
What?
先生  請關閉手機
Sir, kindly switch off your mobile phone.
馬上就好
Just one sec, please.
勞駕
Excuse me?
先生  快坐下
Sir, please sit down.
機長  機艙內有意外
Captain, there's a medical emergency.
有位乘客在過道暈倒了
A passenger has just failen down in the aisle.
新德里  印度101號航班
Deihi, air India 101
緊急情況請求返回
returning due to medical emergency.
醒醒  先生
Excuse me, sir.
慢著
Hold on!
我沒事了  多謝
I'm fine now, thanks.
你們請回吧
Carry on, please.
別走  先生
Gentleman, wait.
-找到車了  -迪隆先生嗎
- Get the car! - Mr. Dhillon?
非得把名字紋腦袋上嗎
Want the name tattooed?
快上車
Get the car!
去酒店嗎  先生
To the hotel, sir?
對  但往沃森特·威哈那兒開
Yes, yes, but via Vasant Vihar.
開快點  伙計
Step on the gas, dude!
法爾漢嗎
Yeah, Farhan?
快點  5分鐘后我來接你
Get ready. I'll pick you up in five minutes.
怎么了
What happened?
查特來電話了  記得他嗎
Chatur called. Remember him?
那個"消音器"?
The 'silencer'?
是的  他說蘭柯回來了
Yeah, he said Rancho is coming.
什么
What?
他說8點學校水塔見
He said come to the campus at 8 on the tank.
你大爺的
Oh shucks!
快點
Hurry!
好
Ok.
親愛的  我很快回來
Honey, I'll be back soon.
鞋子
Oh, shoes.
我們的朋友有消息了
We found our buddy.
什么
What?
回頭再說  拜
Tell me later, bye.
你沒穿褲子
You forgot your pants.
那么現在去酒店嗎  先生
Now to the hotel, sir?
是的  但還要再去下皇家工程學院
Yes, but via Imperial College of Engineering.
好吧  先生
Ok, sir.
忘穿襪子了
Forgot my socks.
不只襪子
More than just your socks,
還有褲子
your pants.
不是吧
Oh no.
馬上去機場接我哥
Now get my brother from the airport.
跟我一個姓的
Same as the name Dhillon.
我是迪隆啊
This is Dhilion.
車子在哪里
Where's my cab?
還沒到嗎
On the runway?
蘭柯
Hey Rancho.
查特  蘭柯在哪兒
Hey Chatur, where's Rancho?
蘭柯
Rancho.
蘭柯人呢
Where's Rancho?
歡迎啊  白癡們
Welcome, idiots!
來點葡萄酒嗎
Some 'Madeira' for you?
跟你們這幾天喝的朗姆差不多
The same Rum you guzzled those days.
試試
Have a drink.
蘭柯在哪兒
Where is Rancho?
別急  先看看這個
Patience. First look at this.
別盯著我老婆看
Don't eye my wife.
看后面的豪宅  白癡
Check out the mansion behind, idiots.
350萬
$ 3.5 million.
泳池帶溫泉的
Swimming pool-heated!
客廳實木地板的
Living room-maple wood flooring!
還有最新款蘭博基尼6.496L
My new Lamborghini 6496 cc
速度超快
Very fast.
給我們看這些干嗎
Why're you showing us all this?
忘了?
Forgot?
這是什么
What's this?
9月5號  今天日期啊
'5th Sseptember'. Today's date.
9月5日
我們打賭
I challenge you.
10年后再見
We'll meet again after ten years.
老時間  老地點
Same day. Same place.
看看誰混得更有人樣
We'll see who's more successful!
沒種了嗎
Have the balls?
怕什么  來啊
C'mon, bet!
想起來了?
Remember?
就在這兒  我跟那白癡打的賭
I'd challenged that idiot right here.
我兌現承諾  回來了
I kept my promise. I'm back.
混蛋
Jackass!
我飛機都沒坐  他褲子也沒穿
I aborted a flight, he forgot his pants,
就是為了趕著見蘭柯
all to meet Rancho.
五年來杳無音信
5 years we've searched.
我們都不知道他是不是還活著
Don't know if he's alive.
你卻以為他會為了那個愚蠢的賭就會來
And you think he'll show up for your silly bet.
我知道他不會來
I know he won't show up.
你揍他還是我來...
You gonna break his jaw or should I...
那你干嗎叫我們來
So why'd you call us here?
見蘭柯
To meet Rancho.
順便看看我們都混得怎么樣
Come and see where I've reached and where he rots.
你知道蘭柯在哪兒
So you know where Rancho is?
是的
Yes.
哪兒
Where?
他在西姆拉
He is in Shimla.
他如風隨行
Free as the wind was he
像疾飛的風箏
Like a soaring kite was he
去向何方  讓我們追尋
Where did he go...let's find him
他如風隨行
Free as the wind was he
像疾飛的風箏
Like a soaring kite was he
去向何方  讓我們追尋
Where did he go...let's find him
我們順著小路前行
We were led by the path we took
他正為自己開辟新徑
While he carved a path of his own
充滿迷惑  充滿新奇  充滿歡樂
Stumbling, rising, carefree walked he
我們的明天充滿未知
We fretted about the morrow
他卻今朝有酒今朝醉
He simply reveled in today
每一分鐘都活得那么充實
Living each moment to the fullest
他到底來自何方
Where did he come from...
觸碰了我們的心然后銷聲匿跡
He who touched our hearts and vanished...
他要去往何方  讓我們找尋
Where did he go...let's find him
在熾熱的太陽下  他是一片綠蔭
In scorching sun, he was like a patch of shade...
在荒蕪的沙漠里  他是一抹綠洲
In an endless desert, like an oasis...
破碎的心  由他為你填補
On a bruised heart, like soothing balm was he
恐懼  我們困在深井之中
Afraid, we stayed confined in the well
無畏  他卻嬉戲于其中
Fearless, he frolicked in the river
毫不猶豫撲向洶涌的潮汐
Never hesitating to swim against the tide
他獨身漫步云端
He wandered lonesome as a cloud
他是我們最親密的朋友
...yet he was our dearest friend
他將去向何方  讓我們追尋
Where did he go...let's find him
蘭柯
Rancho.
蘭柯霍達斯·沙瑪達斯·昌恰德
Ranchhoddas Shamaldas Chanchad.
他就跟他名字一樣那么獨特
He was as unique as his name.
從一開始我們就被灌輸
From birth we were taught
人生就像一場比賽
life is a race,
要么超越別人  要么就落后
run fast or you'll be trampled.
就連生命的誕生
Even to be born,
都是3億精子競爭的結果
one had to race 300 million sperms
我生于1978年下午5點15分
1978, I was born at 5.15 pm.
5點16分  我父親就宣布了
At 5.16, my father announced:
我兒子將來必是工程師
My son will be an engineer.
工程師法爾漢·庫瑞什
Farhan Qureshi. B.Tech. Engineer.
我的命運就這樣被決定
And my fate was sealed.
沒人關心我真的想做什么
What I wanted to be...no one asked.
拉賈·瑞絲奇  蘭柯霍達斯·昌恰德
Raju Rastogi...Ranchhoddas Chanchad.
房號多少
Room number?
D-26
D-26.
跟我走
C'mon.
我叫曼·莫漢
I'm Man Mohan.
這些工程師們都叫我小個子
These engineers call me millimeter.
我賣雞蛋  面包  牛奶還有洗衣服
For eggs, bread, milk, laundry,
代寫學報  復印課堂筆記
finishing journals, copying assignments.
我全包  一口價  拒絕還價
I'm your guy. Fixed rates. No bargaining.
等下  拿著
Hey wait, hold this.
這是小千  小兆  還有他們老媽小億
Meet Kilobyte, Megabyte and their mother Gigabyte.
能摸的  他們不咬人
Go ahead, this family doesn't bite.
跟他打個招呼  那個虔誠的教徒
Check him out...another God-fearing soul.
你好  我是法爾漢·庫瑞什
Hi, Farhan Qureshi
我是拉賈·瑞絲奇
I'm Raju Rastogi
別擔心
Don't worry.
用不了多久他就回歸塵世間了
A few days here and he'll lose faith in God.
?暀W掛滿靚妞  然后念叨著
Then naked babes will be on the wall, and he'll say
神啊  賜我個妞吧
oh God, give me one chance with her.
快滾出去
Get out of here!
4塊錢  一個包2塊
Four bucks. Two per bag.
給你5塊  不用找了
Here's five. Keep the change.
謝了  老板
Thanks boss.
給你個小提示做為報答
For your tip, here's one in return
今晚穿上你最性感的內褲
wear your best underwear tonight.
為什么
Why?
我敬愛的陛下  您崇高偉大
Your majesty, thou art great.
請接受這謙卑的問候
Accept this humble offering.
這家伙夠男人
Here's a he-man.
這瓣真漂亮
What a pretty piece.
可愛又翹
Cute and compact.
學校的老規矩  第一天報道...
A campus tradition-on day 1...
新人必須對學長們表示一下尊敬
Freshmen must pay their respects to seniors,
以脫到只剩內褲的方式
in their underwear.
這是我們第一次見到蘭柯
This is when we first saw Rancho.
蜘蛛俠
Spiderman.
蝙蝠俠
Batman.
新鮮貨色
Fresh meat.
先問候一下
Greetings.
然后脫掉褲子  蓋個章
Drop your pants, get stamped!
叫什么
Name?
蘭柯霍達斯·沙瑪達斯·昌恰德
Ranchhoddas Shamaldas Chanchad.
真拗口  要好好記一下
What a mouthful! Needs serious cramming.
來吧  脫褲子
Come on, pants off.
這么不乖?
Being stubborn?
褲子濕了可不好受  老兄
Wet pants not good, kiddo.
快脫掉
Take them off.
什么
What's that?
他剛說什么
What did he say?
誰來告訴他  詹姆斯·邦德
Someone tell him. Hey James Bond.
教教他規矩
Make him understand.
快脫褲子吧  不然他們會在你身上撒尿
Take off your pants or they are going to piss on you.
零零柒  說母語很丟臉嗎
Hey 007! Ashamed to speak Hindi?
抱歉  我是烏干達人  在龐第皆瑞上的學
Sorry sir, I was born in Uganda, studied in Pondicherry.
所以不太懂印度話
So little slow in Hindi.
那就說慢點  別急
So explain slowly. No hurry.
冷嗎
Feeling cold?
脫褲子  不然他就對你尿刑伺候
Pray undress or he'll do 'urine-expulsion' on you.
尿刑伺候
Calls pissing 'urine-expulsion'!
真是太有才了
A true linguist in the land of engineers!
別躲起來
Hey, come out of there.
快出來  不然...
Come out or...
不然我就對你的門尿刑伺候
Or I'll do 'urine-expuision' on your door.
我數到10  你還不出來的話
If you aren't out by the count of ten,
我以后每天都對你的門尿刑伺候
I'll do 'urine-expulsion' on your door all semester.
One.
Two.
Three.
Four.
Five.
Six.
Seven.
Eight.
Nine.
Ten.
鹽水可以做為電的導體
Salt water is a great conductor of electricity.
初中生都知道
8th grade physics.
我們只學了課本
We had studied it.
他卻學以致用
He applied it.
韋魯·薩哈斯布達教授是ICE的校長 [皇家工程學院的縮寫]
Dr. Viru Sahastrabuddhe was the director of ICE.
學生們都稱他為病毒  電腦病毒
Students called him Virus, computer virus.
病毒入侵  還帶著蛋
Virus on the way, with eggs.
新生們集合  動作快點
Freshmen are summoned. Come quickly!
病毒是我見過最好勝的人
Virus was the most competitive man we had ever seen.
他無法忍受任何人超越他
He couldn't bear anyone getting ahead of him.
為了節約時間  他襯衫用魔術貼
To save time, his shirts had velcro.
領帶是直接勾上去的
And his ties had hooks.
他鍛煉自己用兩只手同時寫字
He'd trained his mind to write with both hands simultaneously.
每天下午兩點小睡一會兒
Everyday at 2 PM he took a 7 minutes power nap,
聽著歌劇入眠
with an opera as lullaby.
戈爾文
Govind,
他的仆人  按命令行事
his valet, had instructions,
卻總是做些沒有意義的事情
to carry out all unproductive tasks.
比如修面  剪指甲等等
Such as shaving, nail-cutting etc.
-這是什么  -鳥窩  先生
- What is this? - Sir, nest.
-誰的  -這只杜鵑的
- Whose? - A koel bird's nest, sir.
錯
Wrong.
杜鵑從不自己做窩
A koel bird never makes her own nest.
她在別人窩里下蛋
She lays her eggs in other nests.
當她們的蛋孵出來后  會怎么做
And when they hatch, what do they do?
她們把其他的鳥蛋推出去
They push the other eggs out of the nest.
這樣就沒有了競爭對手
Competition over.
他們生來就是殺手  這就是大自然
Their life begins with murder. That's nature.
生死殊斗
Compete or die.
你們就像杜鵑
You also are like the koel birds,
而這些就是你們為了進ICE所打破的蛋
and these are the eggs you smashed to get into ICE.
記住  ICE每年要收到40萬份申請
Don't forget, ICE gets 400,000 applications a year.
只有200份能脫穎而出  就是你們
And only 200 are selected - you!
剩下這些呢
And these?
事實證明
Finished.
都成了破碎的蛋
Broken eggs.
我兒子...他努力了三年
My son...he tried for three years.
每次都被拒了
Rejected. Every time.
記著  人生就像一場競賽
Remember, life is a race.
如果你不跑快點就注定被別人超越
If you don't run fast, you'll get trampled.
跟你們說個有意思的事情
Let me tell you a very interesting story.
這是支太空筆
This is an astronaut pen.
鋼筆和圓珠筆在太空里無法使用
Fountain pens and ballpoint pens don't work in outer space.
所以科學家們花費了百萬研發出這支筆
So scientists spent millions to invent this pen.
它可以用在任何情況下
It can write at any angle,
任何溫度中甚至失重狀態下
in any temperature, in zero gravity.
有天  我那時還是學生
One day, when I was a student,
我們院主任給我打了個電話
the director of our institute called me,
"韋魯·薩哈斯布達"  他叫我名字
he said, 'Viru Sahastrabuddhe.' I said, 'yes sir.'
讓我去他那里  當時我有點惶恐
'come here!' I got scared.
他給我看了這支筆
He showed me this pen.
跟我說那是成功的標志
He said, 'this is a symbol of excellence.'
"我把它贈予給你"
'I give it to you,'
"當你遇到一個跟你同樣優秀的人"
'when you come across an extraordinary student like yourself
"把這個傳給他"
...pass it onto him.'
32年了  我一直在等那個人出現
For 32 years, I've been waiting for that student.
但都沒能如愿
But no luck.
在場各位  誰想贏得這支筆
Anyone here, who'll strive to win this pen?
很好
Good.
放下手
Put your hands down.
需要我發布在公告欄上嗎
Shall I post it on the notice board?
放下手
Hands down.
有個問題  校長
One question, sir.
如果鋼筆不能在太空使用
Sir, if pens didn't work in outer space,
那為什么宇航員不用鉛筆
why didn't the astronauts use a pencil?
這樣他們就能省下那筆錢
They'd have saved millions.
我一會兒回答你
I will get back to you on this.
他昨晚弄倒一個學長
He zaps a senior's privates at night.
今天又讓校長當眾出糗
Fingers the director in the day.
我們最好離他遠點
Best avoid him.
你銼了校長的銳氣
You deflated Virus's erection.
我敬愛的陛下  您崇高偉大
Your majesty, thou art great.
請接受這謙卑的問候
Accept this humble offering.
別扯了
Buzz off.
你不用上學嗎
You don't have school?
誰給學費  你老爸嗎
Who'll pay for it? Your pop?
-不許再提我老爸  -稍安勿躁
- Keep off my Dad! - Relax.
上學不用交學費  關鍵是校服
For school you don't need tuition money, just a uniform.
選個學校  買套校服  偷偷溜進去
Pick a school, buy the uniform, slip into class.
大家都穿一樣的  沒人會注意到你的
In that sea of kids, no one will notice.
-萬一被發現了呢  -那就重新找個學校
- If I get caught? - Then new uniform, new school.
-看到沒  -他確實不一般...
- See that? - He was different...
他敢于挑戰所有的規則
He challenged conventions at every stage.
一只熱愛自由的鳥兒占據了病毒的鳥窩
A free-spirited bird had landed in Virus's nest.
我們就像機器人  只會盲從著教授
We were robots, blindly following our professors' commands.
他是唯一一個與眾不同的
He was the only one who was not a machine.
機器是什么
What is a machine?
你笑什么呢
Why're you smiling?
教授  我兒時的夢想就是學工程
Sir, to study engineering was a childhood dream.
我很高興實現了夢想
I'm so happy to be here finally.
用不著這么高興  告訴我機器是什么
No need to be so happy. Define a machine.
機器就是減少人勞動力的東西
A machine is anything that reduces human effort.
你能說明白點嗎
Will you please elaborate?
任何使工作簡化
Anything that simplifies work,
節約時間的工具都是機器
or saves time, is a machine.
夏天天熱  只要按下按鈕  就會產生氣流
It's a warm day, press a button, get a blast of air.
電風扇  就是機器
The fan...A machine!
跟遠方的朋友聊天
Speak to a friend miles away.
用的電話  就是機器
The telephone...A machine!
計算機一秒百萬次換算
Compute millions in seconds.
計算器  也是機器
The calculator...A machine!
我們被機器所包圍
We're surrounded by machines.
無論是小小的筆尖還是褲子拉鏈
From a pen's nib to a pants' zip
全是機器的
all machines.
能快速拉上拉下
Up and down in a second.
上  下  上  下
Up, down, up, down...
那到底定義是什么
What is the definition?
我剛剛已經回答你了  教授
I just gave it to you, sir.
你考試的時候會這么寫嗎
You'll write this in the exam?
這就是機器  又上  又下
This is a machine - up, down...
白癡  還有誰會
Idiot! Anybody else?
就你吧
Yes?
教授  機器就是各種部分的結合體
Sir, machines are any combination of bodies so connected.
按照設定的指令工作
That their relative motions are constrained.
通過信號傳送
And by which means, force and motion may be transmitted.
使用螺絲等工具或者利用杠桿原理
And modified as a screw and its nut, or a lever arranged,
對樞軸的支點或滑輪進行調試
to turn about a fulcrum or a pulley about its pivot, etc.
尤其是其構造幾乎都由復雜的
Especially, a construction, more or less complex
活動零件組裝而成
consisting of a combination of moving parts,
或由簡單的機件部分
or simple mechanical elements,
如輪子  杠桿  凸輪等
as wheels, levers, cams etc.
棒級了
Wonderful!
非常好  請坐下
Perfect. Please sit down.
謝謝
Thank you.
教授  我說的是一樣的   表達得更簡潔
But sir, I said the same thing, in simple language.
喜歡少說話  那就去學藝術或者貿易
If you prefer simple language, join an arts and commerce college.
但是  我們必須搞明白
But sir, one must get the meaning too.
課本那種填鴨式教育到底想表達什么
What's the point of blindly cramming a bookish definition?
你覺得你比課本聰明嗎
You think you're smarter than the book?
把書上的概念背下  除非你不想通過考試
Write the textbook definition, mister, if you want to pass.
-但是也有的書...  -給我出去
- But there are other books... - Get out!
為什么
Why?
說簡單點  出去
In simple language, out!
白癡
Idiot!
我們剛才討論了機器的定義...
So, we were discussing the machine...
你怎么又回來了
Why're you back?
我落了東西
I forgot something.
什么
What?
一種包括記錄  分析  總結  組織
Instruments that record, analyze, summarize, organize,
討論  解釋于一體的
debate and explain information;
分為有插圖  無插圖
That are illustrated, non-illustrated.
硬裝本  平裝本  有封面  無封面
Hard-bound, paperback, jacketed, non jacketed.
附有前言  介紹  目錄  索引
With foreword, introduction, table-of-contents, index.
意在啟發  理解
That are intended for the enlightenment, understanding,
豐富  提升并培養人類大腦思維
enrichment, enhancement and education of the human brain.
通過想象力延伸  間或感受
Through the sensory route of vision, sometimes touch.
你在說什么
What do you mean?
書  教授
Books, sir.
我忘了拿書  能拿嗎
I forgot my books. May I?
你就不能說簡單點嗎
Couldn't you ask simply?
我剛才試過了  不過好象行不通
I tried earlier, sir. It simply didn't work.
教授幾乎不讓蘭柯上他的課...
Professors kept Rancho mostly out...seldom in.
每當被轟出去  他就溜去上別的課
When thrown out of one class, he'd slip into another.
他說  第一年和最后一年是學知識的
He said - first year or fourth year, it's knowledge.
要抓緊
Just grab it.
他特立獨行
He was unlike any of us.
我們每天早上為了洗澡而爭搶
We fought for a shower every morning.
他只要有水就能洗
He'd bathe wherever he found water.
早  教授
Morning, sir.
他對機器充滿熱情
Machines were his passion.
能拆的他都拆
When he spotted them, he opened them.
有的能恢復原狀...
Some he could re-assemble...
有些卻不能
Some he couldn't.
還有另一個跟他很像的人
There was another, just like him.
喬伊·洛博
Joy Lobo.
校長  等等  校長
Sir. Excuse me, sir.
喬伊·洛博先生
Mr. Joy Lobo!
校長  我想問下畢業儀式是哪天...
Sir, if I could know the convocation dates...
怎么了
Why?
我父親要訂火車票
Dad wants to make train reservations.
我是俺們那村第一個工程師
I'm the first engineer from my village.
大家都想來看看
Everyone wants to attend.
要是那樣的話  給你爸打電話
In that case, call your Dad.
動作快點
Please hurry up.
別浪費我時間
Don't waste my time.
喂?
Hello.
爹  校長要跟你說話
Dad, the director wants to speak to you.
喬伊
Joy!
洛博先生  你兒子今年不能畢業
Mr. Lobo, your son won't graduate this year.
怎么了  校長
What happened, sir?
他總是拖延功課
He has violated all deadlines.
洛博先生
Mr. Lobo,
不切實際的東西用來干嗎
it's an unrealistic project.
一天到晚擺弄那些無聊的飛機
He is making some nonsense helicopter.
建議你不要訂火車票了
I suggest you don't book your tickets.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
校長  我可以畢業的  校長
Sir, I am this close, sir.
你的課題完成了嗎
Is your project ready?
校長  請你看一眼這個
Sir, see it once, please.
把課題交上  學校才會考慮下
Submit it, and we'll consider.
校長  再給我點時間
Sir, a small extension...
為什么  我為什么要再給你點時間
Why, why should I?
我爸中風后的兩個月我都沒辦法集中精力
After Dad's stroke, I couldn't focus for two months.
那你飯也不吃了嗎
Did you stop eating?
不是
No.
澡也不洗了?
Stopped bathing?
不是
No.
那你為什么不學習
So why stop studying?
校長  我真的快弄好了
Sir, I'm very close.
求你了  就看一眼...
See it once, please...
洛博先生
Mr. Lobo!
我兒子星期天下午從火車上摔下來死了
Sunday afternoon, my son fell off a train and died.
星期一早上我還是照常去上課
Monday morning, I taught a class.
所以別跟我說這些廢話
So don't give me that nonsense.
我同情你  但不會給你延長時限
I can give you sympathy, not an extension.
校長  我真的快要做好了...
Sir...I'm very close...
我的這一生
Life long I lived.
都為著別人而活
The life of another.
哪怕只有一瞬間
For just one moment,
讓我為自己而活
let me live as I...
我的這一生
Life long I lived.
都為著別人而活
The life of another.
哪怕只有一瞬間
For just one moment,
讓我為自己而活
let me live as I...
給我點陽光  給我點雨露
Give me some sunshine. Give me some rain.
再給我一次機會讓我重新成長
Give me another chance I wanna grow up once again.
給我點陽光  給我點雨露
Give me some sunshine. Give me some rain.
再給我一次機會讓我重新成長
Give me another chance I wanna grow up once again.
這家伙的設計棒得驚人
Dude's come up with an amazing design.
給直升機裝上無線攝像頭
A wireless camera atop a helicopter.
可以用于查看實時路況和安全監管
Can be used for traffic updates, security.
但是病毒那老頭說這個設計不實用
But Virus said it's an impractical design.
它不會飛
It won't fly.
它會飛的  我們能讓它飛起來
It will fly! We'll make it fly.
別告訴喬伊  給他個驚喜
Don't tell Joy. It'll be a surprise.
我們可以讓它飛到他窗口拍下他的反應
We'll fly it up to his window and capture his reaction.
如果我們幫他做項目  誰來幫我們做
If we work on his project, who'll work on ours?
筆試口試測試  每學期有42場考試
Tests, vivas, quizzes - 42 exams per semester.
兄弟你真容易退縮
You scare easily, bro.
把你的手按在胸口說  平安無事
Take your hand, put it over your heart, and say, 'aal izz well'.
-平安無視?  -是平安無事啦
- All is well? - Aal izz well.
精神領袖蘭柯霍達斯的至理名言
Words of wisdom from his holiness guru Ranchhoddas.
我們村以前有個巡夜老人
We had an old watchman in our village.
每次他巡夜的時候就會喊  平安無事
On night patrol, he'd call out, 'aal izz well'.
我們就睡得很安穩  后來來了個小偷
And we slept peacefully. Then there was a theft.
我們才知道那老頭有夜盲癥
And we learned that he couldn't see at night!
他只是喊句平安無事  我們就感到安全
He'd just yell 'aal izz well', and we felt secure.
從那天我明白了  我們的心很容易動搖
That day I understood this heart scares easily.
你得學會哄它
You have to trick it.
不管問題多嚴重
However big the problem,
告訴你的心  "伙計  平安無事"
tell your heart, 'all is well, pal'.
這能解決問題嗎
That resolves the problem?
不能  但是你得到了面對問題的勇氣啊
No. But you gain courage to face it.
學著點兄弟  我們很快就會需要這個的
Learn it up, bro. We're gonna really need it here.
當生活失去控制  就動動你的嘴唇
When life spins out of control just let your lips roll.
動動你的嘴唇  用口哨吹走煩惱
Let your lips roll and whistle away the toll.
當生活失去控制  就動動你的嘴唇
When life spins out of control just let your lips roll.
動動你的嘴唇  用口哨吹走煩惱
Just let your lips roll and whistle away the toll.
大喊平安無事
Yell - all is well...
雞們不知道蛋的命運
The chicken's clueless about the egg's fate.
是孵化還是變成蛋卷
Will it hatch or become an omelette.
沒人知道未來會怎樣
No one knows what the future holds.
所以動動你的嘴唇  用口哨吹走煩惱
So let your lips roll and whistle away the toll.
用口哨吹走煩惱  平安無事
Whistle away the toll yell. All is well.
兄弟們  平安無事
Hey bro. All is well.
哥們  平安無事
Hey mate. All is well.
兄弟們  平安無事
Hey bro. All is well.
困惑越來越多  解決方法卻沒幾個
Confusion and more confusion no sign of any solution.
終于有了辦法  等等  問題是什么
Finally a solution but wait. What was the question?
如果懦弱的心  怕得快要死了
If the timid heart with fear is about to die.
用一個簡單的謊言  讓它不再害怕
Then con it bro, with this simple lie.
心是個傻瓜  它會相信你的話
Heart's an idiot, it will fall under that spell.
動動你的嘴唇  用口哨吹走煩惱
Let your lips roll and whistle away the toll.
用口哨吹走煩惱  平安無事
Whistle away the toll yell. All is well.
兄弟們  平安無事
Hey bro. All is well.
哥們  平安無事
Hey mate. All is well.
兄弟們  平安無事
Hey bro. All is well.
酒能讓獎學金泡湯  卻不能讓憂愁跑掉
Blew the scholarship on booze but that did not dispel my blues.
熏香點燃我的命運  而神靈卻不見蹤影
Holy incense lit up my plight and yet God's nowhere in sight.
小羊羔不知道自己命運
The lamb is clueless for what it's destined.
是被烤還是剁成肉醬
Will it be served on skewers or simply minced.
沒人知道未來會怎樣
No one knows what the future holds.
所以動動你的嘴唇  用口哨吹走煩惱
So let your lips roll and whistle away the toll.
用口哨吹走煩惱  平安無事
Whistle away the toll yell. All is well.
兄弟們  平安無事
Hey bro. All is well.
哥們  平安無事
Hey mate. All is well.
兄弟們  平安無事
Hey bro. All is well.
當生活失去控制  就動動你的嘴唇
When life spins out of control just let your lips roll.
就動動你的嘴唇  用口哨吹走煩惱
Just let your lips roll and whistle away the toll.
平安無事
All is well.
雞們不知道蛋的命運
The chicken's clueless about the egg's fate.
是孵化還是變成蛋卷
Will it hatch or become an omelette.
沒人知道未來會怎樣
No one knows what the future holds.
所以動動你的嘴唇  用口哨吹走煩惱
So let your lips roll and whistle away the toll.
用口哨吹走煩惱
Whistle away the toll.
有了  有了
Eureka! Eureka!
平安無事
All is well.
雞小姐  平安無事
Mrs. Chicken. All is well.
羊羔先生  平安無事
Mr. Lamb. All is well.
兄弟們  平安無事
Hey bro. All is well.
讓它飛到喬伊的窗口去
Hey, take it up to Joy's window.
再高點
Take it higher.
快看屏幕  那哥們光著呢
Look at silencer - the nude dude!
喬伊  快出來
Joy, come out.
到窗戶這邊來
Come to the window.
喬伊  看外面
Joy, look outside.
我放棄
給我點陽光  給我點雨露
Give me some sunshine. Give me some rain.
再給我一次機會讓我重新成長
Give me another chance I wanna grow up once again.
有個好消息  校長
Good news, sir.
警察和喬伊的爸爸都沒有線索
The police and Joy's father have no clue.
大家都覺得是自殺
Everyone thinks this is suicide.
尸檢報告說
The post mortem report
死亡原因是氣管壓力過大
Intense pressure on windpipe
導致窒息
resulting in choking.
大家都覺得他死于氣管壓力
All think the pressure on the jugular killed him.
那這4年來的精神壓力呢
What about the mental pressure for the last four years?
報告里沒提
That's missing in the report.
工程師是群聰明人
Engineers are a clever bunch.
但他們卻沒能造出可以測量精神壓力的機器
They haven't made a machine to measure mental pressure.
如果他們造出來了  大家都會知道...
If they had, all would know...
這不是自殺  這是謀殺
This isn't suicide...it's murder.
你怎么敢把喬伊的死歸咎于我
How dare you blame me for Joy's suicide?
如果一個學生不能處理好自己的壓力
If one student can't handle pressure,
就是我們的錯了嗎
is it our fault?
生活充滿了壓力  你會總是怪罪別人嗎
Life is full of pressures. Will you always blame others?
我沒有怪你  校長  我怪的是這體制
I don't blame you, sir. I blame the system.
看看這些數據  印度的自殺率排在第一
Look at these statistics. India ranks No.1 in suicides.
每90分鐘  就有一個學生企圖自殺
Every 90 minutes, a student attempts suicide.
自殺死的人比病死的人還多
Suicide is a bigger killer than disease.
我們有些地方錯得很嚴重  校長
Something's terribly wrong, sir.
其他的我不敢說
I can't speak for the rest.
但這里是全國最好的學校之一
But this is one of the finest colleges in the country.
我在這兒管了32年
I've run this place for 32 years.
我們學校的排名從28升到現在第一
We were ranked 28th. Now we're No.1.
那有什么意義  校長
What's the point, sir?
在這里  新想法新發明沒人關心
Here they don't discuss new ideas or inventions.
人們只關心成績  工作  去美國定居
They discuss grades, jobs, settling in the USA.
教我們怎么拿高分  卻沒教我們工程學
They teach how to get good scores. They don't teach engineering.
現在輪到你來教我怎么教書了嗎
Now you will teach me how to teach?
不是  校長  我...
No, sir, I...
校長  我的資料...
Sir, my paper...
韋德顏納森  坐下
Vaidyanathan, please sit down.
這里有位自稱是教授的人
Here is a self-proclaimed professor
他覺得自己比我們的優秀教師還要厲害
who thinks he is better than our highly qualified teachers.
蘭柯霍達斯·昌恰德教授現在給我們上工程學
Professor Ranchhoddas Chanchad will teach us engineering.
我們沒那么多時間陪你耗
We do not have all day.
法哈尼楚特  柏饒拉朱利
你們有30秒時間來定義這兩個詞
You have 30 seconds to define these terms.
可以翻書
You may refer to your books.
找到答案了就舉手
Raise your hand if you get the answer.
讓我們看看誰最快  誰最慢
Let's see who comes first, who comes last.
計時  開始
Your time starts...now.
時間到
Time up.
時間到了  校長
Time up, sir.
沒人找到答案嗎
No one got the answer?
現在把你的人生往回倒一分鐘
Now rewind your life by a minute.
當我問這個問題的時候
When I asked this question,
你們激動嗎  好奇嗎
were you excited? Curious?
為你能學到新知識而高興嗎
Thrilied that you'd learn something new?
有人有這種感覺嗎  校長
Anyone? Sir?
沒有  你們都陷入了一場瘋狂的比賽
No. You all got into a frantic race.
這樣的方法有什么用  即使你拿了第一
What's the use of such methods, even if you come first
你的知識多了嗎  不  多的只有壓力
will your knowledge increase? No, just the pressure.
這里是大學  不是高壓鍋
This is a college, not a pressure cooker.
就算是馬戲團的獅子也會因為害怕被鞭打
Even a circus lion learns to sit on a chair
而學會坐在椅子上
in fear of the whip.
但是你們只會說這只獅子是訓練得好
But you call such a lion "well trained",
而不是教育得好
not "well educated".
喂
Hello!
這不是哲學課  解釋那兩個詞就好了
This is not a philosophy class. Just explain those two words.
校長  這兩詞根本不存在
Sir, these words don't exist.
只是我兩個朋友的名字  法爾漢和拉賈
These are my friends' names. Farhan and Raju.
安靜
Quiet!
亂來  你就這么教工程學嗎
Nonsense! Is this how you'll teach engineering?
校長  我不是在教工程學
Sir, I wasn't teaching you engineering.
你才是工程學的專家
You're an expert at that.
我只是在教你  怎么教書
I was teaching you how to teach.
我相信總有一天你能學會
And I'm sure one day you'll learn.
因為我不像你  我不會放棄我的差生
Because unlike you, I never abandon my weak students.
再見  校長
Bye, sir.
安靜
Quiet!
我說了  安靜
Quiet, I said.
我很遺憾地通知您  您的兒子...
I regret to inform you that your son...
法爾漢  拉賈
Farhan. Raju.
由于交友不慎
Has fallen into bad company.
如不盡快撥亂反正  將前途盡廢
Without urgent corrective steps, his future will be ruined.
病毒的信像原子彈一樣投到了我們的家里
Virus's letters dropped on our homes like atom bombs.
廣島和長崎一片廢墟
Hiroshima and Nagasaki plunged into gloom.
我們的父母把我們叫回家狠狠地罵了一頓
Our parents invited us for a dressing down.
進來
Come in.
看到沒?
See that?
我們只用得起一臺空調
We could afford just one air-conditioner.
我們把它放在法爾漢的房間
We put it in Farhan's room,
讓他可以安心學習
so he could study in comfort.
我買不起車  就騎個小摩托
I didn't buy a car. I manage with a scooter.
我們把所有的錢都花在法爾漢的教育上了
We put all our money into Farhan's education.
我們犧牲了自己的享受來換取法爾漢的未來
We sacrificed our comforts for Farhan's future.
你懂嗎
Understand?
這些是你照的嗎  法爾漢
You took these pictures, Farhan?
他曾經的無用嗜好
He had that useless obsession for a while.
到處去給動物拍照
Went around taking pictures of animals.
想做個野生動物攝影師
Wanted to be a wildlife photographer.
兒子  那年你考了多少分
Son, what was your score that year?
91分
91%.
聽到了吧  從94分直掉到91分
Hear that? Straight drop from 94% to 91%.
你覺得這很好笑嗎
You find it funny?
不是的  先生  對不起
No, sir, sorry.
我是被這些照片逗樂了
I'm just amazed at the photos.
為什么讓他當工程師
Why make him an engineer?
為什么不讓他做個野生動物攝影師
Why not a wildlife photographer?
夠了
Enough!
算我求求你了  別毀了我兒子的前途
I humbly request you - don't ruin my son's future.
飯好了  小伙子們  來吧
Food's on the table, boys. C'mon.
如果你下次拜訪  再和我們一起吃飯吧
If you ever visit again, do eat with us.
爸爸沒讓我們吃飯
Dad denied us a meal.
所以  為了填飽肚子
So, to fill our bellies with food.
我們帶著滿耳的訓斥去了拉賈家
And ears with more reprimands, we reached Raju's house.
拉賈的家就跟五十年代
Raju's house was straight out of
黑白電影里的一樣
a 50's black and white film.
一個窄小陰暗的房間
A small, dingy room.
一個癱瘓在床的父親
A paralyzed father.
一個咳嗽不停的母親
A coughing mother.
還有一個嫁不出去的姐姐
And an unwed sister.
一張彈簧外露的沙發
A sofa sprouting springs.
24小時自來水供應  就是屋頂漏的
A 24 hour water supply - from the leaking roof.
母親是個退休教師  喋喋不休地抱怨
Mother was a retired school teacher and a tireless complainer.
父親曾經是郵政局長
Father was once a postmaster.
癱瘓讓他的身體失去了部分功能
Paralysis shut down his body partly.
和全部的薪水  至于姐姐...
His salary completely. And the sister...
甘默已經28歲了
Kammo's turned 28.
他們要輛車做嫁妝
They demand a car in dowry.
如果你不學習不掙錢  她怎么嫁得出去
If you don't study and earn, how will she marry?
要秋葵嗎
Some okra?
秋葵現在12塊一公斤  花椰菜是10塊
Okra is now 12 per kilo, cauliflower is 10.
簡直是搶劫
It's daylight robbery!
如果你被學校警告了  我們以后吃什么
What will we eat if we get warnings from your college?
媽
Mom!
要白軟干酪嗎
Cottage cheese?
白軟干酪應該放天鵝絨盒里擺珠寶店賣
Cottage cheese should be sold at the jewelers, in velvet pouches.
-要白軟干酪嗎  -不  不用了
- Cottage cheese? - No, no, it's ok
媽  別這樣
Mom, please.
好  我閉嘴
Alright, I'll shut up.
要養家糊口  要做牛做馬
Earn for the family, slave like a maid.
還不給說話
And then take the vow of silence.
不跟我兒子說我還能跟誰說
If not with my son, with whom do I share my woes.
跟我兒子的朋友說嗎
His friends?
拉賈
Hey Raju.
我們進退兩難
We were in a huge dilemma.
不知該安慰我們的朋友還是他媽媽
Do we comfort our friend or console his Mom?
管他的  還是吃我們的干酪先
Screw it, we thought, let's focus on the cottage cheese.
現在連他的濕疹膏也要55塊了
Even his eczema cream costs 55 now.
再來塊烤肉嗎
Another roti?
不用了  謝謝  我們飽了
No, thank you. We're through.
秋葵12塊  花椰菜10塊
Okra for 12, cauliflower for 10.
至少你們還吃了頓飯
At least you were offered a meal.
哪像你那個虐待狂老爸  簡直就是希特勒
Uniike your sadistic Dad. "Hitler" Qureshi!
那你媽就是修女特雷莎
And your Mom is mother Teresa.
請我們吃濕疹烤肉
Feeding us 'eczema roti'!
-不許笑我媽  -夠了  你們倆
- Don't poke fun at my Mom! - Enough, you guys.
餓死了  我們去吃東西吧
I'm famished. Let's eat out.
都月底了 誰付錢啊
It's month end. Who'll pay?
他媽媽特雷莎付啊?
His mother Teresa?
出去吃不用帶錢
To eat out,
只要穿禮服就行了  看
you don't need money. Just a uniform. Look.
-走吧  -走
- C'mon. - Come.
晚上好  晚上好
Good evening, good evening.
哎呀  老舅啊
Oh, uncle.
-3大杯伏特加  -一半蘇打  一半水
- Three large vodkas. - Half soda, half water.
我們要是被抓到就死定了
If we're caught, we're dead.
-開胃菜有什么  -要雙倍的
- What's for starters? - Get double portions.
把這個留這兒  去放點歡快的音樂
Leave this here and start some peppy music.
琵雅  這是什么鬼東西
Pia, what the hell is this!
你為什么要戴這個破古董一樣沒用的表
Why're you wearing this ancient piece of junk?
人們會怎么說  我的未婚妻...
What'll people say? My fiancee...
一個前途無量的醫生
A doctor in the making,
卻帶著個才200塊的廉價表
wearing a cheap, 200 watch!
把它摘下來  謝謝
Please take it off. Thank you.
你好  帥哥
Hi handsome.
姨媽  你看起來真漂亮
Hey aunty. You're looking good.
快看我的首飾  親愛的
Don't miss my set, darling
紅寶石的吧
Rubies?
-曼德勒來的  -曼德勒啊
- From Mandalay. - Mandalay.
-過來見見大衛  -好的
- Hey, let's go meet David - Of course.
打擾一下
Excuse me.
怎么了
Yes?
這花送你
Flowers.
-介意我拿著玻璃杯嗎  -為什么
- May I take the glass? - Why?
這樣你就不會用它來砸我腦袋了
So you don't break it on my head.
我為什么要那么做
Why would I do that?
因為我現在要給你的免費建議
For the free advice I'll now impart.
是什么
What?
不要嫁給那個混蛋
Don't marry that ass.
什么
Excuse me?
那貨不是人  那貨是個價格標簽
He's not a human, he's a price tag.
他會把你人生變成只有牌子和價格的噩夢
He'll turn your life into a nightmare of brands and prices.
他會毀了你的生活和前途的
He'll ruin your life. Your future will be finished.
要讓我演示給你看嗎
Want a demonstration?
讓我來告訴你他的鞋是多少錢的怎么樣
Shall I find out the price of his shoes?
我不問  他就會自己告訴我
I won't ask. He'll announce it himself.
操  哪個孫子把薄荷醬灑我300刀的鞋上了
What the hell. Mint sauce on my $300 shoes!
為了你的人生快跑吧  這是免費建議
Run for your life! It's free advice.
聽不聽隨你
Take it or leave it.
真正的意大利皮革  手工的
Genuine italian leather - hand-stitched!
爸  他們是你的客人嗎
Dad, are they your guests?
是我的學生  他們在這干什么
My students. What're they doing here?
爸  等等
Hold on, Dad.
這些豆聞起來真香
These beans smell great.
-沒地方放烤肉了  -堆到上面去
- No room for roti. - Just pile it on.
真是讓人大開眼界  太謝謝你了
That was an eye-opener. Thank you so much.
這是我的道德義務
It was my moral responsibility.
能再幫我個小忙嗎
Can I ask you for little more help?
我爸不會讓我毀掉這個婚約的
Dad won't let me break off this engagement.
你比較會說  能不能也給他演示一下
You explain so well. Can you give him a demo too?
當然  拉賈  薄荷醬
Certainly. Raju, the mint sauce.
你真好人
You're really sweet.
-你爸爸在哪兒  -就在你后面
- Where is your Daddy? - Right behind you.
平安無事
Aai izz well.
為了你的人生快跑吧  這是免費建議
Run for your life! It's free advice.
聽不聽隨你
Take it or leave it.
你們在這里干什么
What're you doing here?
我們來把這些禮物交給新婚夫婦
We'll hand these gifts to the couple.
我幫你吧  這是我姐姐的婚禮
I'll do that for you. It's my sister's wedding.
姐姐?
Sister?
校長  你有幾個女兒啊
Sir, what's the sum total of your daughters?
空的  沒有支票
Empty. No gift cheques.
怎么把支票忘了  拉賈...法爾漢
Forgot the cheques, Raju...Farhan?
我們沒邀請你  你們是新郎的客人吧
We didn't invite you, you must be from the groom's side.
不  校長  我們代表著科學而來
No sir, we're here as the emissaries of science.
什么意思  你能解釋一下嗎
How? Can you explain?
爸爸  他這么能言善辯
Dad, he explains superbly.
我相信他會給我們一個解釋的
I'm sure he'll give us a demo.
對吧
Won't you?
新德里經常發生停電...
Well, Delhi has plenty of power cuts that...
這會打斷婚禮的行進
Disrupt wedding celebrations.
所以我想造個能從客人的汽車里抽取電能
So I thought of making an inverter that
的換流器
draws power from guests' cars.
我懂了
I see.
那換流器在哪兒呢
So where's the inverter?
校長  設計圖已經完成了的
Sir, the design is ready.
設計圖在哪兒呢  法爾漢
Where's the design, Farhan?
-我把它給你了的  -我給了拉賈
- I gave you the design - I gave it to Raju.
拉賈  設計圖呢
Raju, design?
別管設計圖了  我會造出換流器給你看
Never mind the design. I'll make the inverter and show you.
你只會造謠  哪會造什么換流器啊
You can only invent stories, not an inverter.
我會做出來的  我保證
I'll make one, I promise.
而且還會以您來命名
And I'll name it after you.
畢竟  這是在你女兒的婚禮上發明的
After all, it was invented at your daughter's wedding.
很榮幸...
So it'll be an honor...
法爾漢  拉賈  明天到我辦公室來
Farhan, Raju. I'll see you in my office tomorrow.
校長  每盤多少錢  我們還您
Sir, what was the cost per plate? We'll reimburse you.
...不過得按揭
...in instailments.
我們絕不會再亂闖婚禮了
We'll never crash a wedding again.
哪怕是我們自己的婚禮
Not even my own.
事實上  我甚至不會結婚  他也不會
In fact, I won't even marry. Nor will he.
對...不結婚
Uh...right. No marriage.
你們的父母也不該結婚
Your parents shouldn't have married either.
這世界本來可以少養兩個白癡的
The world would have to feed two less idiots.
坐下
Sit!
聽好了
Pay attention.
這是蘭柯霍達斯父親的月收入
This is Ranchhoddas's father's monthly income.
去掉兩個零也還是一筆可觀的收入
Couple of zeroes less, and it's still a sizeable income.
但是再去掉一個零  我就有點擔心了
But erase another zero, and I would worry a little.
這不是你爸爸的收入嗎  法爾漢
Isn't that your fathers income, Farhan?
是的  校長
Yes, sir.
再去掉一個零
Now take away another zero.
就變成你全家的收入了  賈·瑞絲奇
And that's your family income, Raju Rastogi.
真讓人擔心啊
Big reason to worry.
接受我的建議  搬去跟查特·雷曼寧甘一起住
Take my advice and shift into Chatur Ramalingam's room.
馬上要考試了
Exams are here.
你們再跟蘭柯混下去肯定不及格
Stay with Rancho and you're sure to fail.
-要刮胡子嗎  -不用  校長
- Want a shave? - No, sir.
那還不快滾
Then get lost!
別擔心  拉賈
Raju, don't worry.
病毒想要分裂我們  分而治之
This is Virus's move to split us. Divide and rule.
我不得不擔心
I have to worry.
他給我們打分
He grades us,
我需要個好分數來找個好工作
and I need good grades for a good job
我們不像你  有個有錢的爸爸
Unlike you, I don't have a rich Dad I can live off.
閉嘴  拉賈
Shut up, Raju.
我們非要聽他的廢話嗎  平安無事
Must we follow all his hogwash? 'aal izz well'
我才不會像你一樣當他的跟班
I won't be his flunky like you.
你有點過分了
You're crossing the line.
不  我是在畫好界限
No, I'm drawing one.
我要養家糊口
I have a family to support.
我爸的醫藥費花光了我媽的退休金
Dad's medicines swallow up Mom's pension.
我姐嫁不出去  因為他們要一輛車做嫁妝
My sis can't marry because they want a car in dowry.
我媽已經5年沒買過一件新的紗麗服了
Mom hasn't bought a single saree in five years
不要把你媽的衣柜也扯到這個問題里來
Now don't get your Mom's wardrobe into the debate.
順便問下  一年買幾件紗麗服才正常
By the way, how many sarees per annum is reasonable?
別開我媽的玩笑
Hey...no wisecracks about Mom.
我們要用心學習  而不是只為求個分數
We'll study with all our heart, but not just for grades.
智者說  學習是以修煉氣質而不為斂財
To quote a wise one -- study to be accomplished, not affluent
以優秀自律  成功自會隨你而來
Follow excellence, and success will chase you, pants down!
哪個智者說過這話
Which wise one says this?
又是精神領袖蘭柯霍達斯?
His holiness guru Ranchhoddas?
別扯淡了
Go rot in the bogs!
拉賈  放輕松  我們會考第一的  萬事皆有可能
Raju, don't stress. We'll top our class. Nothing is impossible.
萬事皆有可能?  真的嗎
Nothing is impossible? Oh yeah?
塞回管子里
Shove this back into the tube.
拉賈選擇了另一條路
Raju got onto another train.
他在查特手下的悲慘命運開始了
His travails with Chatur began.
沒錯  是悲慘命運  不是快樂的旅程
Yes, I mean travails, not travels.
查特綽號"消音器"
Chatur was called "silencer".
為了歷練自己的記憶力
To sharpen his memory,
他向一位赤腳庸醫求了幾粒藥丸
he popped pills from a local quack.
從此以后放屁不出聲  卻奇臭無比
And then let off silent...but lethal farts.
不是我...是拉賈放的吧
I didn't do it...Raju?
自己放屁卻總讓別人背黑鍋
He always blamed others for the output.
消音器每天苦讀18個小時
Silencer crammed 18 hours a day.
考試前夕  則想方設法分散他人注意力
On exam eve, he would distract others.
他堅信--人生登頂之路只有兩條
His belief -- there are only two ways of topping:
抬升自己的分數或者壓低對手的分數
elevate your own grades or shrink your opponents' grades.
蘭柯則想出了絕妙的辦法
Rancho decided to subdue silencer and rescue Raju
來幫助拉賈  消滅"消音器"
with one master plan.
我們的導師孜孜不倦地服務于...
Our director has unceasingly served...
"服務"的意思是...
"served" means...
管他什么意思  記住就行
Damn the meaning, I'll memorize it.
查特負責在教師節那天致詞
Chatur was the introductory speaker at the teachers' day function.
為了給病毒留下深刻印象
To impress Virus,
他找圖書管理員幫忙
he got his speech written by the librarian
寫一篇浮夸絢麗的文章來
in highbrow Hindi.
你好  稍等  查特  有電話
Hello. Hold on. Chatur, call for you.
幫我收一下打印稿  我去去就回
Please collect the printout. I'll be right back.
而我要做的是
Oh...the things I have to do.
杜別先生  校長念叨您呢
Mr. Dubey, the director was remembering you.
-真的嗎  -沒錯  剛還念叨呢
- Really? - Yes. Just now.
我這就去見他  把這個交給查特
I'll see him right away. Give this to Chatur.
你好  喂?
Hello. Hello.
你好  雷曼寧甘先生嗎
Hello, Mr. Ramalingam?
什么事啊
Yes?
這里是警察局
I'm calling from the police station.
-你是烏干達來的嗎  -是的  長官
- Are you from Uganda? - Yes, sir.
你現在有生命危險
Your life is in danger.
什么  怎么回事
What? How?
聽好了  否則...
Listen carefully, or else...
你一邁出校門就得一命嗚呼
You'll get killed as you step out of the college gate.
為什么  出什么事了
Why? What happened?
查特被纏住的當兒
While Chatur was kept engaged,
蘭柯改了改演講稿里的幾個詞
Rancho altered a few words in his speech,
比如  把"服務"改成"壓榨"
for eg, 'served' became 'screwed'.
校長在嗎
Yes, sir?
-你是誰  -我叫杜別  圖書管理員
- Who are you? - Dubey. Librarian.
校長  我是終身任職的
I'm permanent staff, sir.
恭喜你
Congratulations.
等一下  警長在和我通話
Hold on a moment. The chief is on the other line.
喂?  你好
Excuse me, sir
那...我該去哪兒呢
Yes...so where was I?
你說我死定了...只要一出校門
You said I may die...outside the gate.
沒錯  你一出大門就會看見紅綠燈
Right. As you get out of the gate, you'll see a traffic signal.
紅綠燈  好的
Traffic signal. Ok.
紅燈亮時  所有的車輛都會停下來
When it turns red, all the cars will halt.
對  然后呢
Ok. Then?
小心翼翼地穿過馬路
Then cross the road with great caution.
因為孩子  在高峰時段被車撞的話
Because son, in rush hour if a car hits you,
就死定了
you're dead.
扯淡  我知道啊
What nonsense! I know that.
你知道了  好的  這樣你安全了
You know that? Excellent. Then you're safe my boy.
管理員給你的  消音器
From the librarian, silencer.
不許那么叫我  昌恰德
You don't call me that, Chanchad.
校長說他沒找過我
Hey. The director said he didn't call for me.
誰說他找你了  我是說他念叨你呢
Who said 'called'? I just said he 'remembered' you.
念叨?  你個淘氣包
Remembered? Rascais!
尊敬的主席先生
Distinguished Mr. Chairperson.
各位貴賓  令人敬仰的教育部長
Chief guest, the honorable minister of education.
各位敬愛的老師  同學們
Respected teachers and friends.
ICE的招牌已名揚四海
Ice has now soared beyond the stratosphere.
一切的溢美之詞
The credit goes solely to
卻都涌向韋魯·薩哈斯布達博士
Dr. Viru Sahastrabuddhe.
熱烈歡迎他
Give him a big hand.
校長  聲音是他的
Sir, the voice is his
可講稿卻出自我之手啊
but the words are mine.
他是一個偉人  您名副其實
He's a great guy, really you are.
32年來  他孜孜不倦地壓榨學生
For 32 years, he has unceasingly screwed students.
他是想說  "服務"學生
He means - 'served' students.
我堅信他的努力還將繼續
I'm sure his endeavors will continue.
我們不得不為他震驚  憑一己之力
We are astounded at how one man,
在一生中  竟可以壓榨如此多的學生
in one lifetime can screw so many,
且壓榨地淋漓盡致
so well.
他不斷地訓練以保持活力
With rigorous training he's built up his stamina.
他將生命的每一分鐘投入到壓榨中去
He's spent every living minute just screwing.
讓我們繼續他的事業
Let's replicate his methods.
明日我校的學生將走向世界各地
Tomorrow Ice students will go across the globe.
無論我們去往何方
Wherever we go,
我們都會將壓榨進行到底
we promise to screw.
我們會讓壓榨者的旗幟在全世界飄揚
We'll hoist this screwer's flag all over the world.
我會向世人展示我們壓榨的水平
We'll show the world that our capacity to screw
在地球上
cannot be matched by any student
將無人能及
anywhere on the planet.
部長先生  晚上好
Mr. Minister. Good evening.
您給予這所學院急需的東西
You have given this institution what it sorely needs.
-基金  -咪咪
- Booty, funds. - Bosom.
是基金  蠢貨  咪咪的意思是...
It's booty, stupid. Bosom means...
扯淡  太侮辱人了
What nonsense! That's insulting.
人人都有咪咪  但它被遮住了
Everyone has a bosom, but it remains pocketed.
沒有人愿意輕易奉送
No one offers it so readily.
同學們
Vulgar fellow!
你們無私地奉獻出了自己的咪咪
You have generously offered your bosom
將它交給了這位永不知疲憊的壓榨者
to this relentless screwer.
讓我們看看  他是如何使之變大的吧
Now see how he makes it grow.
校長  你就教這些東西嗎
Is this what you teach here, director?
在這莊重的時刻  我愿引用梵文一句
On this august occasion, here's a sanskrit verse.
且聽--屁的力量
Listen to this -- the might of his fart in verse.
神圣崇高的屁是如此令人崇敬
A good loud fart is honorable
"屁"?  繼續  消音器
'fart'? Go, silencer.
半響的屁是可以忍受的
A medium fart is tolerable.
輕微的小屁實在可怕
Softer windbreaks are terrible.
而悠悠然的無聲屁則最令人發指
And the silent ones unbearable.
這如同毫無意義的死記硬背
That's what mindless cramming does to you.
死記硬背陪伴你大學時代
Cramming may see you through four years of college.
而且它將陪伴你走過人生的另外40年
But it will 'screw' you for the next 40 years.
他還沒發覺問題呢
He still doesn't get it.
"半響屁可以忍受"...難以置信
'medium fart is tolerable'...unbelievable!
蘭柯  你真是位詩人
You're a poet, rancho.
你咋想出來這招的
How did you think of this?
這樣多有趣  他都不知道哪兒觸犯了部長
That was fun. He didn't know what hit him.
你這頭豬  我平日怎么待你的
You swines! What did I ever do to you?
不要生氣  別放在心上啊
Sorry man. Don't take it personally.
怎么別放心上
I will.
查特·雷曼寧甘
Chatur Ramalingam
將永遠不會忘記這個侮辱
will never forget this insult.
我會每分每秒都記著這一刻的
I'll think of it every minute, every second of my life.
對不起  這只是給拉賈上了一課
Sorry man. That was a demo for Raju
不要盲目死記硬背啊
don't cram blindly.
要理解  享受科學的種種奇跡
Understand and enjoy the wonders of science.
我來這兒可不是為了享受科學的
I'm not here to enjoy science.
你是來這兒壓榨科學的
So you're here to screw science.
繼續啊  繼續嘲笑我的方式
Go ahead. Laugh at my methods.
總有一天我的方法會給我帶來成功的
But one day these methods will bring me success.
到那時  看誰笑到最后
That day I'll laugh and you'll cry.
你已誤入歧途  別追逐成功了
You're on the wrong track again. Don't chase success.
好好當個工程師  成功會不請自來的
Become a good engineer and success will chase you.
這些理想在現實世界里是行不通的
These ideals don't work in the real world.
你走你的陽關道  我過我的獨木橋
You take your train, I'll take mine.
十年后的今天  讓我們在此再會
Ten years from now we'll meet at the same station.
老時間  老地點  看看誰混得更有人樣
Same day. Same place. We'll see who's more successful.
是你...還是我
You...or I.
沒種了嗎  怕什么  來啊
Have the balls? C'mon, bet!
我們打賭
It's a challenge.
快看
Watch it!
他寫什么呢
What's he writing?
不要忘了這個日子
Don't forget this date.
太貴重了  我接受不了  蘇哈斯
I'm not used to such expensive gifts, Suhas.
你得適應啊  琵雅
Get used to them, Pia.
你要做蘇哈斯的嬌妻了
You're gonna be Suhas tandon's wife.
開票吧  伙計
Where's the bill, man?
稍等
I'll be back.
-你改了演講稿?  -什么
- You changed the speech? - What?
別撒謊
Don't lie.
恩...沒錯
Um...yeah.
你和我爸有什么深仇大恨
What's your problem with Dad?
沒仇沒恨
I have no problem.
我在發明一臺以他名字命名的換流器
I'm making an inverter named after him.
看...
Look...oh
你為什么總找他麻煩
Why're you harassing him?
因為他是在辦工廠  不是學校
'cause he runs a factory, not a college.
批量培養混蛋  就像那樣
Churning out asses. Like that one.
他親手毀了學校
He destroyed it, man.
你竟敢叫他混蛋
How dare you call him an ass?
他就是  先當工程師  然后讀MBA
He is one! First engineering, then MBA.
去美國的銀行工作
Then becomes a banker in the USA.
就因為這樣賺的錢更多嗎
Because it rakes in more money?
對他來說  生活就是一張盈虧表
Life for him is just a profit-loss statement.
他看到了你身上的價值  就利用你
He sees profit in you, so he's with you.
校長千金  又是個醫生...
Director's daughter, doctor in the making...
為自己打造形象
good for his image!
他在乎的不是你
It's not you he cares for
你以為自己是誰啊
Who do you think you are?
你說他不在乎我是什么意思
What do you mean he doesn't care for me?
新表?  等一下
New watch? One moment.
你總喜歡看我演示一下
You always need a demo.
蘇哈斯
Hey Suhas.
你們干嗎呢
Where were you?
她找她的新表呢
She's looking for her watch.
什么  你弄丟了那塊表?
What? You lost the watch?
沒事  再買一塊就行了
Never mind. Get another.
那要40萬呢
It cost 400,000!
我的表只有250塊  走得一樣準
Mine's just 250, but keeps the same time.
閉嘴...
Keep quiet...
你怎么能這么不小心呢  琵雅
How could you be so careless, Pia?
你這種滿不在乎的態度真是太糟了
This callous attitude is disgusting.
太無禮了
It's disrespectful.
那是一塊限量版的表
That was a limited edition watch.
好吧  戴著你那塊古董垃圾去吃晚餐吧
Now wear your ancient piece of junk at dinner.
你看什么看
What're you staring at?
要準備來哭的了  成熟一點  琵雅
Here come the tears! Real mature, Pia.
我受不了這個
I can't handle this.
別哭了  好好找找
Stop crying and look for it.
這表  另找他人來戴吧  混蛋
Find another wrist for this watch...ass!
你太帥了  當面罵他混蛋啊
Hey, you're awesome. Called him an ass to his face.
滾開
Get lost.
這兒太吵了
It's too noisy here.
她該說"謝謝"  我聽的卻是"滾開"
She's saying 'thank you', I hear 'get lost'.
-我說"滾開"  -別搞得這么難堪嘛
- I said 'get lost'.  - Don't get so uptight
事實上  你從來就沒有真的愛上過他
Actuaily, you never really loved him.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
當你看著他時  風兒悄悄把故事傳送?
When you see him, do the winds whisper a melody?
你的頭巾緩緩飛舞?
Your scarf flies in slow motion?
明月當頭?
The moon appears gigantic?
這是電影里的情節  不是現實生活
That happens in movies, not in life.
生活中也會出現的
Happens in life too。
當你真的愛一個人的時候
If you love a person,
而不是一個混蛋
not an ass.
喂?  怎么了
Hello. What?
天哪  好的  我馬上來
Oh God! Ok, I'm on my way.
你是學醫的  對嗎  需要你的幫助
You're a medicai student, right? Need your help.
-緊急情況  拜托了  -什么事
- It's an emergency, please.  - What?
請先跟我來  你們醫生的誓言怎么說的
Please come with me. What's that oath you doctors take.
你們絕不拒絕病人的求援  真夠虛偽的
You'll never deny a patient help...the hippocratic oath.
請幫幫我  情況緊急
Please help me, it's an emergency.
你先是來我姐姐婚禮上吃霸王餐  然后又攪亂了我的訂婚
You gatecrash my sister's wedding, break off my engagement.
因為你  爸爸不得不吃藥
My Dad is popping bp pills because of you.
我還得在這兒幫你
And here I am, helping you!
真是難以置信
Unbelievable!
虛偽的誓詞  真是害慘我們了
This hippocratic oath -- it's really done us in!
-拉賈在哪兒  -去找出租車了
- Where's Raju, Ma'am?  - Gone to get a cab.
2個小時前就找急救車了
Called the ambuiance two hours ago.
在咱們國家  披薩都要送半小時
In this country, pizza reaches in 30 minutes
更何況是救護車啊
but an ambulance!
他需要趕緊住院治療  情況緊急
He needs hospitalization. Urgently.
停車
Hey stop!
閃開  緊急情況
Move, it's an emergency!
閃開  閃開
Move...move...
醫生  這里有緊急情況
Doctor, emergency!
有病人
That's the patient
拿著  拉賈來了
Keep this. Hey, here's Raju.
怎么回事  你們開著摩托車送爸爸來的?
What the hell! You brought Dad on the scooter?
我應該打包送快遞公司嗎
Should I've sent him by courier?
別在要命的關頭開玩笑  他人呢
No wisecracks on dads profession! Where is he?
去問問醫生吧
Go ask the doctor.
琵雅  真是千鈞一發啊
Close call, Pia.
再晚一點  就回天乏術了
A little delay, we'd have lost him.
幸好你們用摩托車送他過來
Glad you didn't wait for an ambuiance
而不是等救護車
and got him on the scooter.
有問題盡管找我
Call me if there's a problem
蘭柯  謝謝你
Rancho! Thank you.
謝謝你的兄弟們吧
Thanking your buddies!
消音器沒教你做人的規矩嗎
Silencer isn' teaching you manners?
他沒告訴你  朋友是人最棒的咪咪嗎
Didn't he teach you -- a friend is man's greatest bosom?
走吧  明天有考試的
Go on now. You have an exam tomorrow.
考試多著呢  爸爸卻只有一個
Exams we have many, Dad mostly just one.
我們不會撇下郵政局長先走的
We won't budge from here without the postmaster.
別擔心了
Don't worry.
蘭柯  原諒我吧  我那時是害怕了
Rancho, forgive me. I was scared.
沒事了  好了
It's ok. Quiet, now.
請原諒我
Please forgive me.
沒事了  靜靜吧  去看看你爸爸
It's ok, calm down. Go see your Dad.
別帶著一臉淚水去看他
And don't go with that weepy face.
謝謝你  兄弟
Thanks buddy.
摩托車真方便  救了一條命  多少錢買的
Natty scooter. Saved a life. How much does it cost?
灑點薄荷醬上去  我就告訴你
Pour some mint sauce on it. It'll tell you.
獨立日快樂
Hey, happy independence day.
今天不是獨立日
Today isn't independence day.
對你來說就是
For you it is!
從今以后你就可以隨心所欲戴你媽的表了
Now you're free to wear your Mom's watch.
沒人再敢說它是塊古董垃圾了
No ass can say it's an ancient piece of junk.
你怎么知道那是我媽媽的表
How do you know it was Mom's watch?
在你姐姐的婚禮上  你穿著閃閃的新衣
At your sister's wedding, you wore sparkling new clothes.
唯獨表是舊的
Only the watch was old.
怎講
What could that mean?
那天  你格外思念媽媽  不是嗎
You really missed your Mom that day, didn't you?
是啊
Yes.
你媽媽肯定非常美麗
Your Mom must've been really beautiful.
對啊  你怎么知道
Yes. How do you know?
看到你爸爸了嗎
Seen your Dad?
"人生是場競賽  要是你不跑"
'life is a race. If you don't run fast.
"就只有死的份兒...布谷鳥"
You'll be a broken egg...cuckoo bird'
你...
You...
微風低語  輕送旋律
The winds whisper a melody
天空也跟著哼唱
The sky hums along
時間歌唱
Time itself is singing
我愚笨的心兒
My silly heart goes
七上八下啊
as it jives and jigs along
我愚笨的心兒
My silly heart goes
七上八下啊
as it jives and jigs along
樹葉在枝上輕唱  蜜蜂群舞花心
Leaves sing on their branches bees jam with flowers
陽光在花瓣上歡舞
Crazy sunbeams dance off petals
小鳥在天空里歡歌
as birds yodel in the skies
花兒啊  大膽而無所顧忌的相擁
Flowers, bold and brazen snuggle
這電影的場景在你我之間上演
I've seen it happen in movies what's now happening with us
我那愚笨的心兒
My silly heart goes
七上八下啊
as it jives and jigs along
我愚笨的心兒
My silly heart goes
七上八下啊
as it jives and jigs along
讓我們制作獨特而又永?琲瑭〃?醬吧
Let's make the unique and ever useful mint sauce
這萬能的醬定能測出誰是濫竽充數的騙子
The all-powerful sauce that exposes phony people
你的第七間屋子已打掃干凈
Your 7th house is clear
躲過混蛋  你定遇得到好人
Shunning an ass, you'll fall for a human
時機已到  戀愛吧
Time is ripe for love
新德里的氣溫保持穩定
Temperature in new Delhi remains stable
天氣晴朗
Clear skies.
但是對于戀愛的人來說  下雨才好呢
But if in love, expect rain
雨滴淅淅瀝瀝隨風飛舞
Pitter-patter go the raindrops whish-whoosh whistles the wind
如同華爾茲  在天地間回蕩
Do-da-dee waltzes the rain boom-boom echoes the sky
讓大雨濕透你的全身
Drenched in rain and
點燃你的熱情  隨著音樂晃動你的臀部
passion you sway your hips on cue
電影里的場面  在我們的生活中上演
I've seen it happen in movies what's now happening with us
我愚笨的心兒
My silly heart goes
七上八下啊
as it jives and jigs along
我愚笨的心兒
My silly heart goes
七上八下啊
as it jives and jigs along
那低沉的月  那么迷人
The gorgeous low moon
為地球唱響小夜曲
serenades the earth
流星劃過  低吟一曲愛的民謠
A shooting star skips along crooning a ballad of love
夜如此亮  可寂寞來襲  英俊的你
The night is bright but lonesome come touch me, my handsome
電影的場景在你我生活中上演
I've seen it happen in movies what's now happening with us
我愚笨的心兒啊
My silly heart goes
七上八下啊
as it jives and jigs along
我愚笨的心兒
My silly heart goes
七上八下啊
as it jives and jigs along
我愚笨的心兒啊
goes my silly heart
早上好  醒醒啦
Hello. Wake up.
-郵政局長死了?  -什么
- Huh...postmaster's dead?  - What!
沒有啦  笨蛋
No, stupid.
8點半了  你們的考試在9點
It's 8.30, your exam is at 9.
可我們不能把他一個人留在這兒啊
But we can't leave him alone.
有我在  不就3個小時嘛
I'm here. It's a matter of three hours.
騎我的摩托車去吧  要遲到了
Take my scooter. It's getting late.
天哪  真是塊古董表
Gosh, what an ancient watch.
快走吧
Go.
-對不起  我們遲到了  -有緊急情況
- Sorry, we're late.  - It was an emergency.
坐著吧
Settle down there.
老師  他們還在寫呢
Sir, they're still writing.
好了  時間到
Hello. Time up.
拜托  再5分鐘  我們遲了半個小時
Please, five minutes. We started half an hour late.
是有緊急情況
It was an emergency.
他盯著我們好像我們要了他的腎一樣
He glared at us like we'd asked for both his kidneys.
我們繼續寫
But we continued writing.
他則接著整理卷子
He continued arranging the answer sheets.
好了  老師
Done, sir.
你們遲了  我不收了
You're late. I can't accept these.
老師  拜托了
Sir, please, sir.
你知道我們是誰嗎
Sir, do you know who we are?
首相的兒子嗎  就算是...
Prime ministers son? Even then...
我也不會收你們的卷子的
I will not accept your paper.
你知道我們的名字和學號嗎
Do you know our names and roll numbers?
不知道
No.
你們是誰
Who are you?
他不知道哈  快跑
He doesn't know, run!
你們的學號是啥
Hey, what's your roll number?
你們的卷子哪兒去了
Where the heil are their papers?
神啊  行行好吧
O lord, have mercy.
今天就是出分數的日子
Today was results day.
讓我們和神靈來個交易吧
Time to make a deal with God.
讓我的電子課學過了吧  我愿敬獻椰肉
Just save my electronics. I'll offer a coconut.
神蛇先生  保佑我的物理成績吧
Sir snake, biess my physics.
我保證每天敬獻一品脫牛奶
I promise a pint of milk per day.
神牛啊  保我通過吧  請吃這鮮草
O mother cow, heip me pass...have this grass.
不再有關于姑娘的淫蕩想法
No x-rated thoughts of girls in my class.
關照一下我的成績吧
Watch over my results.
財神  我愿每個月敬獻100塊
God of wealth, I'll offer 100 every month.
100塊還不夠賄賂交警呢
100 won't bribe even a traffic cop,
更別說圣賢了
let alone the almighty.
從心底告白
Check from the bottom
你是最后一名
You are...last.
你呢
And you?
倒數第二
Second last.
蘭柯呢
Rancho?
沒他
Not there.
我心一沉
My heart sank.
不是因為我們的糟糕成績啊
Not 'cause our ranks tanked,
是因為我們的朋友不及格
but 'cause our friend flunked.
肯定有問題  這不可能  不公平
There's a mistake. It's not possibie. It's injustice.
消音器為什么哭啊
What's silencer howling about?
他第二名
He got the second rank.
誰是第一呢
Who's first?
蘭柯
Rancho.
蘭柯?
Rancho?
讓開點
Move aside.
朋友不濟  你難過
Your friend fails, you feel bad.
朋友發達  你更難過
Your friend tops, you feel worse.
真傷心  另外兩個更傷心
We were sad. Two others were sadder.
蘭柯霍達斯·昌恰德  第一排  校長右邊
Ranchhoddas Chanchad. Front row. Right of the director.
烏代·錫哈  第二排  第三個座位
Uday Sinha. Second row. Third seat.
艾洛克·米塔爾  二排  第五個座位
Alok Mittal. Second row. Fifth seat.
薩赫利·拉奧  三排...
Sahili Rao. Third row...
校長  為什么根據名次排座位啊
Sir, why this seating according to rank?
不行嗎
Any problem with that?
不是  這個排名制度跟社會等級制度似的
Yes, this grading system is like a caste system.
好像奴隸一樣
Slaves.
-這不太好  校長  -你有更好的建議嗎
- It's not nice, sir. - You have a better idea?
有  成績根本就不應該公開
Yes. Results should not be displayed at all.
為何要公開別人的隱私呢
Why publicise someone's flaws?
如果你缺鐵  醫生是給你開補藥
If your iron count is low, will the doctor prescribe tonic...
還會在電視上廣播你的病例嗎
or air your report on TV?
明白嗎  校長
You see, sir?
這么說來  你的意思是
So basically, what you are saying is
我得親自去每個同學的房間
I should personally go to each student's room.
然后對著他們的耳朵悄悄地說
And whisper in his ears...
你是第一名  你是第二名
'you have come first'; 'you're second';
不好意思  你沒及格
'I'm so sorry, you have failed'
不是這樣  校長  我是說分數劃分等級
No sir, I mean grades create a divide
我是第一名  所以坐在你旁邊
I've topped, so I'm next to you.
我朋友排名在后  就坐在后面的角落
My pais came last, they're in the back corner.
至少他們還能坐在角落里
At least they're in the corner
再跟你混下去  他們連角落都別想坐
More time with you, and they'll be out of the photo.
他們都會不及格  找不到工作
They will neither pass, nor get a job
他們會找到工作的  校長  肯定有公司會...
They'll get jobs, sir. There must be some firm that...
喜歡人類而不是機器
prefers humans to machines.
會找到工作的  我保證
They'll get jobs. I guarantee.
你保證?
You guarantee it!
打賭嗎  校長
Bet, sir?
-戈爾文  -什么事  校長
- Govind. - Yes, sir?
假如他們有人能在校園招聘會上找到工作...
Even if one of them gets a job in campus interviews...
就刮掉我的胡子
Shave off my moustache.
校長
Sir!
-滿意了嗎  -笑一個
- Happy? - Smile, please
滿意了  校長
Happy, sir.
混蛋  按喇叭來掩蓋你的屁聲
Jackass! Honking to hide your tooting.
好像腐爛的味道  你又吃放屁藥啦?
Septic tank! Popping pills again?
不是我  是拉賈放的
I didn't do it. Raju?
好熟悉的臭味啊
This is a familiar stink.
他是全球變暖的始作俑者
He's the sole cause for global warming.
我受不了了
I cannot take it.
錢包給我  我去買條褲子
Toss me your wailet. I'll buy pants.
-穿查特的衣服吧  -別碰我衣服
- Take Chatur's suit instead. - Don't touch my suit.
就算你只穿內褲  蘭柯也認得出你
Rancho'll recognize you even in underwear.
-這地方在哪兒  -我識字的話  還會賣花生嗎
- Where's this? - if I could read, wouid I sell peanuts?
他不識字  但是會說話吧
He can't read, but he can speak.
等下  你認識一個叫蘭柯霍達斯·昌恰德的人嗎
Wait. Do you know a Ranchhoddas Chanchad?
認識  他住那邊
Yes, he lives there.
他如風隨行
Free as the wind was he.
像疾飛的風箏
Like a soaring kite was he
去向何方
Where did he go?
找找他吧
Let's find him.
-查特  你的藥  -謝謝  哪兒找到的
- Chatur, your pills. - Thanks. Where were they?
-口袋里  -我的褲子
- In the pocket. - My pants!
馬克思說過  資源要共享
Karl Marx says to share all resources.
你這樣別人會誤會的
You'll give people ideas.
我現在就想要
I want it now.
怎么了
What happened?
蘭柯的父親
Rancho's father.
請問  蘭柯霍達斯在哪兒
Excuse me, Where is Ranchhoddas?
-在那兒  -謝謝
- There he is. - Thank you.
-蘭柯  -什么事
- Rancho. - Yes?
不好意思  我們找蘭柯霍達斯
Sorry. We're looking for Ranchhoddas.
我就是蘭柯霍達斯
I am Ranchhoddas.
不是  我們找蘭柯霍達斯·沙瑪達斯·昌恰德
No, I mean 'Ranchhoddas Shamaidas Chanchad'.
蘭柯霍達斯·沙瑪達斯·昌恰德  就是我啊
Ranchhoddas Shamaidas Chanchad. That's me.
蘭柯霍達斯  節哀  孩子
Ranchhoddas, take care, son.
蘭柯霍達斯·昌恰德
'Ranchhoddas Chanchad'
拉賈
Raju.
我穿著內褲橫穿新德里到了西姆拉
I'll be in the Guinness book for
都能破吉尼斯了
driving Delhi-Shimla in underwear.
而且還找錯了人
That too, for the wrong guy!
同名  同學歷  同照片  就是不同人
Same name, same degree, same photo, but a different guy.
怎么回事啊
What's going on?
S消音器怎么找到蘭柯地址的
How did silencer get Rancho's address?
說的對
Good point!
查特  過來
Chatur, come here.
你敢打開這個  我從舊金山帶來的
How dare you open this? I got this from San Francisco.
手工餅干
Handmade biscuits.
特意為范素科·旺都先生準備的
Specially for Mr. Phunsukh Wangdu.
范素科·班都?  誰啊
Phunsukh Bangdu? Who's that?
不是班都  是旺都  范素科·旺都
Not Bangdu. Wangdu. 'w'. Phunsukh Wangdu.
你知道他是誰嗎  他是個偉大的科學家
Do you know who that is? He's a great scientist.
400項專利  誰都想得到他
400 patents. The world wants him.
花了我一年的時間才能跟他見面
Took me a year to get an appointment.
只要他跟我的公司簽合同  我就發達了
Once he signs the deal with my company, I'll be huge!
別想旺都了  你怎么找到蘭柯地址的
Forget Wangdu. How'd you get Rancho's address?
這得感謝范素科·旺都
You should be thanking Phunsukh Wangdu.
他告訴我的  看
He led me to Rancho, see this.
我秘書到這里跟旺都預約
My secretary was here to fix an appointment with Wangdu.
她沒預約到  但是我找到了蘭柯
She didn't get the appointment. But I found Rancho.
我查了西姆拉的電話簿  發現了蘭柯的名字
I checked the Shimla directory and found Rancho's name.
他的臉怎么了
What happened to his face?
難道是易容術  以表示與你見面的榮幸?
Plastic surgery in honor of your visit?
只有一個人知道真相
Only one man has the answer.
對不起  爸爸  我無法滿足你最后的心愿
Sorry Papa, I couidn't fulfill your last wish.
你一直讓我帶你去朝圣
You kept asking me to take you on pilgrimage.
我卻等著公路的投標
But I waited for the highway tender.
現在投標好了  你卻閉眼了
There the tender opened, here you closed your eyes.
真對不起  爸爸  我是個不孝之子
I am so sorry, papa. I could not be a good son.
不對
Wrong.
你是工程師  你的學位在?暀W呢
You're an engineer. Your degree's on the wall!
你是個很孝順的兒子
You were a very good son.
你怎么敢闖進來  我要報警抓你們
How dare you barge in? I'll have you arrested.
不  你會被抓起來的  我們查過了
No, you'll be arrested. We've made enquiries.
你靠學位來簽訂合約
You use the degree to clinch contracts.
那是我朋友的學位  你怎么弄來的
It's our friend's degree. How did you get it?
這是150英畝的土地
This is a 150 acre estate.
就算我斃了你  埋掉  也不會有人知道的
If I shoot and bury you, no one would even notice.
明白了嗎
Get the point?
給我滾出去
Now get lost.
我正要帶著父親的骨灰去圣河
I'm taking papa's ashes to the sacred river.
也可以帶上你們的
Can take yours too.
快搶他爹
Grab papa!
這兒  這兒
Here, here.
放了我爸爸
Let go of papa!
說實話  要不就把你爸爸沖走
Tell the truth or papa is flushed!
-還我爸爸  -爸爸要去圣下水道了
- Hand over papa. - Papa goes to the sacred sewer.
把我爸從馬桶上挪開
Get papa out of the potty.
你開槍  我就沖了他
You pull trigger, I pull flush.
數到3
I'll count to three
想殺我們?  拉賈  把骨灰撒進去
Wanna shoot us? Raju, scatter the ashes
One.
要抓我們  爸爸就進排水管了
Take us down, and papa's down the drain
Two.
讓他在下水管中暢游吧
Then grope for him in the gutter.
怎么了  拉賈
What is it, Raju?
我們拿錯壺了  這是空的
We've got the wrong urn. It's empty!
空的?
Empty?
-空的  -我們把它倒掉
- Empty. - We'll empty it out!
不  不
No, no!
我們倒了啊
We'll empty it out.
不  我投降
No. Hands up!
你是誰
Who are you?
我是蘭柯
I am Rancho.
以我爸爸的名義發誓  這是真的
I swear on papa, it's true.
我是蘭柯  他是徹侯特
I am Rancho! That was Chhote.
徹侯特?
Chhote?
他是我家花匠的兒子  徹侯特
He was our gardener's son, Chhote.
他父母去世后  跟我們住一起
He stayed on with us after he was orphaned.
在周圍打些零工  跑跑腿
Did odd jobs around the house, ran errands.
他對學習充滿熱情
He had a passion for learning.
穿著我的舊校服  溜進學校
He'd wear my old uniform and slip into school.
聽他喜歡的課程  這正合我意
And attend any class he liked. It suited me.
我讓他幫我做作業  幫我考試
I made him do my homework, take my exams.
一切都很順利  直到有一天
It was going well, till one day.
老師看到一個六年級的學生做高一的數學題
Our teacher saw a sixth grader doing tenth grade math.
你幾年級  孩子
Which grade are you in, son?
你叫什么
What's your name?
我們被抓了
We got caught.
我爸爸很有權勢  所以...
Papa was a powerful man, so...
在去見校長之前  我們老師提醒他
Our teacher alerted him before going to the principal.
既然你選擇了  就要有始有終
You started it, you will finish it.
人們表面很尊敬我
People pretend to show me respect.
但是在背后
But behind my back...
丫們卻嘲笑我是文盲
mock me as an illiterate.
我不會讓此事發生在我兒子身上
I won't let that happen to my son.
這個孩子想學習  而我只想要個學歷
This boy wants to study. I want just a degree.
就將錯就錯吧
Let the game go on.
讓這孩子做個工程師
Make this kid an engineer.
而我將會在?暀W掛著我兒子的學歷證書
And I'll have a degree in my son's name on that wall.
我去倫敦待了4年  他則替我上大學
I went to London for four years, he went to college as me.
他答應獲得學位后斷絕一切聯系
He'd promised to cut contact with all after getting the degree.
但是他總說  有兩個白癡會來找我
But he always said, 'two idiots will come looking for me'.
他真的很想你們倆
He really misses you both.
我給你們他的地址  去找他吧
I'll give you his address, go to him.
請幫我保守秘密
But please keep my secret.
什么秘密
What secret?
你拿錯罐子了  先生  爸爸在這兒呢
You got the wrong urn, sir. Papa is in here.
到底怎么回事  那個拿槍的家伙是誰
What the hell's going on? Who was that gun guy?
故事復雜  又沒字幕  不適合你
Complicated story. Without subtitles. Not for you.
-別想了  -我們去哪兒
- Ignore it. - Where're we going?
拉達克
Ladakh.
拉達克?  為什么
Ladakh! Why?
去見蘭柯
To meet Rancho.
他在拉達克做什么
What's he doing in Ladakh?
不知道  我們有個學校地址
No clue. We have the address of a school.
學校老師
School teacher!
我是羅克利奇公司的副總裁  而他...
I'm vice president of Rockledge Corporation, and he...
蘋果的果  氣球的球... [諷刺蘭柯教書育人]
A for apple, b for Ball...
蠢驢的驢
D for donkey.
下周我要和范素科·旺都簽一個大合同
Next week I sign a huge deal with Phunsukh Wangdu
而他...蘋果的果  氣球的球...
And he...A for apple, B for Ball...
我對那個傻瓜的敬意從今天起急速提升
Today my respect for that idiot shot up.
大多數人上大學只想得個學位
Most of us went to college just for a degree.
沒學位就沒稱心的工作  沒有嬌妻
No degree meant no plum job, no pretty wife...
沒有信用卡  沒有社會地位
No credit card, no social status.
這些對他都不重要
None of this mattered to him.
他在大學享受學習的樂趣
He was in college for the joy of learning.
從不關心是第一名還是最后一名
He never cared if he was first or last.
誰是登月的第一人
Who was the first man on the moon?
是尼爾·阿姆斯特朗  校長
Neil Armstrong, sir.
顯然  是尼爾·阿姆斯特朗  我們都知道
Obviously, it is Neil Armstrong. We all know it.
誰是第二個呢
Who was the second?
不要浪費時間  這并不重要
Don't waste your time. It's not important.
沒有人會記得第二名
Nobody remembers the man who ever came second.
不久  將會有26家公司前來招聘
Soon, 26 companies will be here with job offers.
你們在期末考試前甚至就可以找到工作
You'll have a job even before your final exam,
這也是最后一搏  朋友們
this is your last lap, my friends.
踩住油門  全速前進
Put the pedal to the metal. Step on the gas.
整裝待發  創造歷史
Go out there and make history!
有疑問嗎
Any questions?
請講
Yes?
校長  假如有個學生找到了工作...
Sir, suppose a student gets a job...
但是期末考試不及格
But narrowly fails the final exam,
他還能得到這份工作嗎
will he still have the job?
問得好
Very good question.
誰有跟他相同的疑問嗎
Anyone else with the same question?
不出所料
As expected.
請到臺上來  給他們點鼓勵
Please come on stage. Give them a big hand.
過去的4年里
For the last four years,
他們是成績最穩定的同學
they've been our most consistent students.
每次考試都很穩定地排在最后
Consistently last in every exam.
來  天才們  來
Come my geniuses, come.
他們的腦袋會值很多錢
Their brains will fetch a handsome price.
因為它們完全沒被用過
'cause they're completely unused.
下面回答他們的問題
And to answer their question.
成績不會影響工作
The exam won't affect their jobs.
因為根本不會有公司雇傭他們
Because no company will hire them anyway!
他們太特別了  他們的名字將用金字鐫刻
They're so unique, their names will be writen in gold.
"法哈尼楚特"和"柏饒拉朱利"
'farhanitrate' and 'prerajulization'
請大家鼓勵鼓勵他們
Give them a big hand, please, everybody.
他羞辱我們
He screwed us!
當著所有人的面
In front of everyone.
神靈啊  我愿從此食素  并點1000根香燭
God, I'll give up meat, light a 1000 incense sticks.
就請幫我一個忙
Do me just one favor.
滅了病毒那個老不死的
Delete virus!
把他燒死在地獄里
Burn him in hell.
在沸油中炸了他
Fry virus-nuggets in bubbling oil.
你覺得神是簽了合約的殺手嗎
You think God is a contract killer?
你閉嘴
You shut up.
你每年都在照片的中間
You're in the center of the photo every year.
我們就爛在角落
We're rotting in the corner.
今年我們也許就不會出現在照片上了
This year we may fall out of the photo altogether.
-知道我為什么第一嗎  -為什么
- Know why I come first? - Why?
因為我喜歡機器
Because I love machines.
我對機器有熱情
Engineering is my passion.
知道你的熱情是什么嗎
Know your passion?
-那是我的包  -閉嘴
- That's my bag. - Be quiet.
你到底想干什么
What're you up to?
這...是你的熱情
This...is your passion.
去寄這封信
Go post this letter.
什么信
What letter?
五年前他寫給最喜愛的
5 years ago he wrote this for his favorite
野外攝影師的信
wildlife photographer.
-安德烈  -伊斯塔萬
- Andre. - Istvan.
特別想認識遠在匈牙利的他
He wanted to train with him in Hungary.
但是因為怕他爸  那個希特勒  他從沒寄出去
But in fear of his Dad, the fuhrer, never posted it.
放棄工程學  投身攝影
Quit engineering, marry photography,
發揮自己的才能
follow your talent.
如果MJ的爸爸強迫他做拳擊手
If Michael Jackson's Dad forced him to be a boxer...
拳王阿里的爸爸逼他做歌手
And Mohammad Ali's Dad pushed him to be a singer...
想想有多可怕
Imagine the disaster.
你明白了嗎
Do you get it?
白癡  喜歡攝影  卻屈身于機器
Idiot! Loves photography, but is marrying machines.
我尊敬的精神領袖蘭柯霍達斯
Your holiness guru Ranchhoddas.
工程學就是我的妻子和情人
Engineering is my wife and mistress both.
但是我還是失敗了  為什么  請解釋
But I still fail. Why? Expiain.
因為你是個懦夫  懼怕未來
'cause you're a coward, scared of the future.
看這個  圣環比手指還多
Look at this. More holy rings than fingers.
一個恐懼一個環  考試  姐姐的嫁妝  工作
One ring per fear - exam, sis's dowry, job.
帶著這些對明天的恐懼  怎么活過今天
With such fear of tomorrow, how'll you live today?
怎么能專注地學習
How'll you focus on studies?
怪兄弟  一個活在恐懼中  一個活在偽裝中
Strange buddies! One lives in fear, the other in pretense.
這兩個你都有  既恐懼又偽裝
You live in both - fear and pretense.
害怕告訴琵雅  你愛她
You're scared to tell Pia you love her...
所以假裝不愛
so you pretend you don't.
我擦  坑爹呢
What rubbish!
講道理簡單  做起來就難了
Easy to offer free advice, tough to foliow it.
有種嗎  去向琵雅表白
Have the guts? Go confess to Pia.
-根本不是一回事  -就是一回事  我的主啊
- There's no connection! - Deep connection, your holiness.
聽著  如果你敢表白
Listen, if you confess to Pia,
我就告訴我老爸  不學工程  改嫁攝影
I'll tell Dad - no engineering, I'm marrying photography.
那我就在招聘前  丟掉我的圣環
And I'll dump my rings before the job interview
干不干
Deal?
有種嗎
Have the guts?
精神領袖無話可說了
His holiness is speechless.
走
Let's go.
-跟我來  -去哪兒
- Follow me. - Where?
走
Let's go.
病毒  我是抗病毒啊
Virus! I'm anti-virus
希望這兒沒有狗
Hope no dog here.
懦夫  走啊
Cowards! Let's go.
如果有危險  我會給出病毒警報的
If any danger, I'll give the virus alert.
小心  病毒在里面
Beware - virus inside.
要背景音嗎
Need background score?
-琵雅  -誰啊
- Pia. - Who's it?
別喊  是我  蘭柯
Don't yell! It's me, Rancho.
就一會兒  我說完就走
Just listen for a moment, then I'm gone.
什么也不用說...
Say not a word...
-琵雅  -什么
- Pia. - Yes?
和你騎摩托的那22分鐘
Those 22 minutes with you on the scooter
是我一生中最開心的22分鐘
were the most enchanting 22 minutes of my life.
我愿意和你在摩托上共度一生
I could spend an eternity with you on the scooter.
...讓時間靜止
...and time stands still.
每晚你都會出現在我的夢中
Every night you ride into my dreams
騎著摩托而來  裝扮得宛如新娘
on your scooter, dressed as a bride.
取下的不是面紗  卻是頭盔
Instead of a veil, you lift your helmet.
信步走來  和我相吻
And come close to kiss me.
不過  卻沒有吻成功
But that kiss doesn't happen.
為什么
Why?
因為鼻子撞了到一起  然后我就醒了
Because the noses collide, and I wake up.
鼻子怎么可能撞到一起  傻瓜
The noses never collide, stupid!
抱歉  我以為你是琵雅
I'm sorry, I thought you were Pia.
希望我是
I wish I was.
姐姐  你為什么打斷他
Sis, why did you interrupt?
他花了4年才說出這些的
It took him four years to say this.
琵雅  吻他  告訴他鼻子碰不到一起
Pia, kiss him. Show that noses don't collide.
我批準了  吻他  太可愛了
You have my permission, kiss him. He's so cute!
-這是誰  -我姐姐
- Who's this? - My sister.
你是誰
Who're you?
你說話的時候  他踢腿來著  是第一次
When you were talking, he kicked. First time!
他?  你怎么知道是"他"還是"她"
He? How do you know it's a 'he' or 'she'?
爸爸問過占星師
Papa asked the astrologer
我是生個工程師還是醫生
if we'd get an engineer or a doctor.
什么意思
Meaning?
男孩是工程師  女孩是醫生
Boy becomes an engineer, girl a doctor.
冠軍  最好待在里面  外面有個馬戲團
Champ, better stay inside. Out here's a circus.
你外公是團長  他會揮舞長鞭
Your grandpa is the ringmaster. He'll crack his whip
"跑  生活就是賽跑  做個工程師"
'Run! Life is a race. Be an engineer'
但你得跟著自己的想法走  如果外公嚇唬你
But you follow your heart. If grandpa scares you...
把手放在胸口  說"平安無事"
Put your hand on your heart and say, 'all is well'.
他又踢了
He kicked.
再說一遍
Say it again.
平安無事
All is well.
又踢了
Kicked again.
-再來  -平安無事
- Once more. - All is well.
平安無事
All is well.
是誰
Who is it?
快走
Go.
你給我爸寄了封討厭的信
You sent hate-mail to Dad,
我回你封尿信
here's pee-mail for you.
好好享受尿信吧  祝你閱讀愉快
Enjoy the pee-mail, happy reading!
-誰啊  -你的未來女婿
- Who is it? - Your future son-in-law.
婚禮聚會上的
And the wedding party.
庫瑞什
Rastogi!
保安  那邊
Security, that way.
這么說你們都學會了簡單鐘擺
So you all have already learned about the simple pendulum.
現在我們開始
Now let's get down to the advanced
進一步學習復擺
study about compound pendulum.
不規則物體圍繞自己的軸震蕩
It's an irregular object osciliating about its own axis.
我來演示給你們看
Let me demonstrate to you.
-這是什么  -鉛筆
- What's this? - Pencil.
-里面是什么  -鉛芯
- What's inside? - Lead.
很好  鉛芯是鉛筆的軸
Good. Lead is the axis to this pencil.
就算你是個復擺  如果你震蕩...
Even you can be a compound penduium, if you osciliate about...
-拉賈·瑞絲奇在哪兒  -到  校長
- Where is Raju Rastogi? - Present, sir.
大家都到了啊
Everybody is here.
早上好  校長
Good morning, sir.
你昨天晚上在哪兒
Where were you last night?
-學習了一晚  校長  -學習?
- Studying all night, sir - Studying?
真的嗎
Really?
兩晚沒睡覺  所以他看起來蓬頭垢面的
Hasn't slept two nights, that's why he looks scruffy.
沒睡覺?
Not slept?
你學什么了
What did you study?
感應電動機  校長  所有章節
Induction motor, sir. The whole chapter.
所有章節?
Whole chapter?
既然這樣  拉賈·瑞絲奇先生
In that case, Mr. Raju Rastogi...
到  校長
Yes, sir!
你能告訴我們感應電動機如何啟動嗎
Can you tell us how an induction motor starts?
關掉它
Stop it.
校長  是朗姆酒
Sir, rum.
瑞絲奇先生
Mr. Rastogi.
我們去辦公室喝杯茶吧
Let's have a cup of tea in my office.
校長?
Sir?
把門關上
Close the door.
會打字嗎
Can you type?
會
Yes, sir.
可以幫我打封信嗎
Will you type a letter for me?
沒問題  校長
Definitely, sir.
來這邊坐
Come, sit.
校長  對不起...
Sir, I'm sorry sir...
開始吧
Please type.
尊敬的先生...
Dear sir...
我很遺憾地通知您...
It is my painful duty to inform you...
您的兒子已被勒令退學
that your son is rusticated...
不  錯了  刪了  重新來
No, sorry, delete that. Go back.
您的兒子  拉賈·瑞絲奇...
Your son, Mr. Raju Rastogi...
已被皇家工程學院勒令退學
is rusticated from the Imperial College of Engineering.
快打啊
Come on, type.
校長  這會要了我爸的命
It'll kill my Dad, sir.
-快啊  -校長  請別這樣
- Please type. - Sir, please sir.
這是最終決定  不予更改
My decision is final and irrevocable.
他為了看我成為工程師  才活到現在
He lives just to see me become an engineer.
你在門口撒尿時  就該想到這點
Should've thought of that before peeing on my door.
校長  求求您了  再給我一次機會吧
Sir, give me one chance...please.
可以  把你名字刪了
Ok, remove your name from the letter...
換成蘭柯
and put in Rancho's.
我知道他昨天和你待一起
I know he was with you last night.
作我的證人  我就放過你
Be my witness and I'll spare you.
給你7分鐘的思考時間
You have 7 minutes to think.
我們不會拋下你
We won't let go of you
我們還要繼續生活
We're not done yet...no way
或許天堂正在呼喚你
The heavens may beckon you
但我們會舉起臂膀與上帝對抗
But we'll take up arms against God
這場戰斗我們絕對不能輸
And it's not a fight we intend to lose
或許你在盡力逃避
You may try your best to escape
用盡你所有的力氣
Try with all your might
但我們絕不會讓你離去
But there is no way we are letting go of you
不會拋下你
We won't let go of you
我們還要繼續生活
We're not done yet...no way
蘭柯  看那監視器
Rancho, watch that monitor.
拉賈?
Raju?
雖然他的身體癱瘓了  但仍然有意識
His body is paralyzed with shock, but his mind is alert.
他能夠看見聽見我們  所以請別在他面前哭
He can see and hear us. Please don't cry in front of him.
和平常一樣跟他說話  鼓勵他  開點玩笑
Speak to him normally, motivate him, joke around, push him.
好消息  拉賈  你爸爸康復了
Good news, Raju. Your Dad's recovered.
新藥起的作用
The new medicine worked.
一個人沒事了  另個就倒下
Is this your family tradition
這難道這是你們家的傳統嗎
as one male gets up, the other conks out?
快醒來
Come, wake up.
你爸爸想要琵雅的摩托車
Your Dad wants Pia's scooter.
我該讓他騎嗎  希望他不要弄壞了
Should I give it to him? Hope he won't dent it.
拉賈  法爾漢想和你視頻  他在寢室里
Raju, Farhan is live on webcam. From the hostel.
快看  病毒把你的退學通知撤銷了
Look, Virus has canceled your suspension order.
問題已經解決了  快醒來吧
Problem solved...wake up now.
都解決了  你聽到了嗎
Everything's resolved! you hear that?
哥們  快起來  動起來
Rise and shine, buddy
在這短暫的旅途中
In this journey of few strides
我們稱之為生活
On the path called life
不要輕言放棄  只需為旅途歡慶
Don't quit...just celebrate the ride
傾聽那些愛你的人們
Listen please to those who love you
每個昏暗的夜晚后  都將迎來陽光萬里
Every dark night is followed by sunrise
請別拒絕那些愛你的人們
Don't shut out those who love you
我們不會拋下你
We won't let go of you
我們還要繼續生活
We're not done yet...no way
我們不會拋下你
We won't let go of you
我們還要繼續生活
We're not done yet...no way
-快看  媽媽買了件新的紗麗  -嶄新的
- Look, Mom bought a new saree. - Brand new.
花了2000塊呢
It cost 2000.
快醒來
Wake up now.
她不止買了一套  是十套
She bought not one, but ten sarees.
快看啊
Look!
醒醒  拉賈
Hey Raju!
快告訴我  這樣好看嗎
C'mon tell me...how do I look?
想起媽媽曾經寫的那些信
Remember the letters Mom would write...
總是保佑你能一生平安
Always blessed you with eternal life
請別傷她的心  請別離開她
Don't die on her...you can't die
看著我們  別轉過身去
Look at us now, don't turn away
笑一次來說明你還在乎我們
Smile once to show you care
醒過來  別再讓我們痛苦
Wake up, don't torment us anymore
你聽說你姐的消息了嗎
Did you hear about your sis?
她要結婚了
She's getting married
什么嫁妝都不需要
without any dowry.
新郎什么都不要
The bridegroom wants nothing at all.
他只想要娶甘默
He just wants Kammo.
你知道新郎是誰嗎
You know who the bridegroom is?
快猜
Guess!
跟你很熟的
You know him very well.
他很喜歡動物
He loves animals.
他要去當一名野生動物攝影師
He's going to be a wiidlife photographer.
輕點...噓
Quiet...shhhh...
還沒猜到嗎  是法爾漢啊
Didn't get it? It's our Farhan.
法爾漢什么嫁妝都不要的
Farhan will never take any dowry.
法爾漢要和你姐姐結婚了
Farhan will marry your sister.
什么都不要  免費的  免費的
For free! Free! Free!
拉賈
Raju!
2斤秋葵  1斤免費奶酪  就能叫醒他
One kilo okra, 500 grams cheese for 'free' would've woken him.
為什么要犧牲我...
Why sacrifice me... !
太棒了  哥們
Well done, buddy.
一切都敲定了  法爾漢要和你姐結婚了
So it's all fixed, Farhan will marry your sister.
蘭柯
Rancho
笨蛋  你坑爹呢
Rascals...stop fibbing.
恭喜你逃掉了
Lucky escape!
我們不會拋下你
We won't let go of you
我們還要繼續生活
We're not done yet...no way
我們不會拋下你
We won't let go of you
我們還要繼續生活
We're not done yet...no way
我們不會拋下你
We won't let go of you
秋葵每公斤12塊
Okra rs.12 kilo
你叫了計程車?
You called for a taxi?
-叫了  -車在外面等了
- I did. - It's waiting.
謝謝  怎么了
Thank you. Why?
我一會兒有個面試
I'm going to the job interview.
你跟我們一起嗎
You coming with me?
不  我去參加面試  你回家
No. I'm going for the interview. You're going home.
為什么我要回家
Why would I go home?
我們答應過這笨蛋的
Remember, we promised this rascal.
把你的領帶給我
Give me your tie.
為什么
Why?
因為你看完這個  就不想去面試了
I doubt you'll go for the interview after reading this.
什么東西
What's that?
-一封信  -匈牙利寄來的
- A letter. - For you, from Hungary.
一位名叫安德烈·伊斯塔萬的攝影師
Some photographer called Andre Istvan.
你把我的信寄出去了
You posted my letter!
他很喜歡你的作品
He loved your pictures.
他想讓你做他的助手
The guy wants you to assist him...
去巴西熱帶雨林待一年
In the Brazilian Rainforest, for a year.
還有工資
Will pay you, too.
我爸絕不會同意的
Dad will never agree.
去和他談談  真心的
Go speak to him...from your heart.
就一次  不要怕
For once, dump your fears...
不然某天你掛了  你會后悔的
Or someday, on your deathbed, you'll regret it.
你會記得手里拿著信
You'll remember that the letter was
計程車在外面
in your hand, taxi at the gate...
只需一點點勇氣  就能改變命運
With just a little courage, you could've turned your life around.
你覺得他會喜歡嗎
Do you think he'll like it?
為什么買這么貴的禮物
Why such an expensive gift?
我們的兒子  今天就要有第一份工作了
Our son's getting his first job today.
在這么值得驕傲的時刻  就不能太小氣
Don't be stingy at such a proud moment.
法爾漢?
Farhan?
你今天不是有面試嗎
Don't you have the job interview today?
我沒去
I didn't go.
爸  我不想當工程師
I don't want to be an engineer, Dad.
怎么了  發生什么事了
What happened? You had an accident?
看到那樓嗎  我從三樓跳下來了
See that building? I jumped from its third floor.
為什么
Why?
因為我被學校勒令退學了
Because I was rusticated from college.
為什么
Why?
酗酒  還在校長家門口撒尿
Drunk, I urinated on the director's door.
那個該死的蘭柯正在腐蝕你的腦子
That scoundrel Rancho is messing with your mind!
我不喜歡工程學  會是個差勁的工程師
I don't enjoy engineering. I'd make a terrible engineer.
蘭柯的想法很簡單  選自己喜歡的
Rancho has a simple belief, make your passion your profession.
這樣工作才會開心
Then work wiil become play.
你在那個叢林里能賺什么錢
What'll you earn in that jungle?
錢雖然很少  但能學到很多
A small stipend, but I'll learn a lot.
5年以后
Five years from now...
當你看到你的朋友們買車
When you see your friends buying cars
買房  你就會后悔的
and homes, you'll curse yourself.
工程師的生活  只會讓我更加沮喪
Life as an engineer will bring only frustration.
那時我會抱怨您的
Then I'll curse you.
我寧愿讓自己后悔
I'd rather curse myself, Dad.
全世界都會嘲笑你
The world will laugh!
在最后一年放棄  你個沒用的東西
Label you a loser, for quitting in the final year.
卡普爾先生覺得你在ICE念書是多值幸運的事
Mr. Kapoor feels you're fortunate to be at ICE.
他會怎么想
What'll he think?
卡普爾先生又沒有給我買空調
Mr. Kapoor didn't provide me with an air-conditioner.
我睡得香時  卡普爾又不會睡得不舒服
It wasn't Mr. Kapoor who slept in discomfort while I slept well.
又不是他  讓我騎在肩膀上  帶我逛動物園
He didn't take me around the zoo on his shoulders.
一切都是您做的  爸爸
You did all that, Dad.
我只在乎您怎么想  他對我一點都不重要
How you feel, matters to me. Mr. Kapoor makes no difference.
我甚至不知道他叫什么
I don't even know his first name.
你當你是情景劇里的英雄嗎
You think you're the hero of a melodrama?
夠了  求你了  他已經很難過了
Enough, please...he's upset.
老天  請別讓他再做像拉賈那樣的傻事
God forbid, if he did something crazy like Raju...
那就沒什么好說的了
Then the discussion is over.
什么都別說了  免得他也跳樓
Don't say a word or his lordship will jump off the roof.
不  爸爸  我絕不會去自殺  我保證
No, Dad. I'll never attempt suicide. I promise.
您討厭的蘭柯把這照片放在我錢包里
The Rancho you detest put this picture in my wallet,
告訴我  每當我有自殺念頭的時候就看看
told me to see it if a suicidal thought crossed my mind.
并想象當您看見我的尸體時
And imagine what'd happen to your smiles
您的笑臉會變成什么樣子
when you see my dead body.
爸爸  我想說服您
I want to convince you, Dad.
但不是以自殺作為威脅
But not with a suicide threat.
爸爸  如果我變成一個攝影師會怎樣
Dad, what'll happen if I become a photographer?
我會賺得很少
I'll earn less.
可能房子很小  車子也很小
I'll have a smailer house, a smailer car.
但我會很快樂的
But I'll be happy.
我會打心底里開心的
I will be really happy.
我為您做的任何事情都是真心的
Whatever I do for you will be out of genuine love.
我以前一直聽您的話
I've always listened to you.
就這一次  請遂了我的心愿吧
For once, let me listen to my heart.
求您了...爸爸
Please...Dad.
爸爸
Dad...
求求您別走
Please don't go away...
把這個退了吧
Return this.
兒子  一臺專業的照相機要多少錢
Son, what's the cost of a professional camera?
這臺筆記本夠換一架嗎
Can the laptop be exchanged for it?
如果你缺錢  只管開口
If you need more money, just ask.
去過你想要的生活吧  我的孩子
Go live your life, my son.
你的成績一直不好  是因為什么
Your grades are consistently poor. Reason?
恐懼
Fear.
我從小就是個好學生
I was a good student since childhood.
父母希望我能夠讓他們致富
Parents hoped I'd end their poverty.
這讓我恐懼
That scared me.
就像比賽  如果不是第一  那什么都不是
Here I saw the mad race. You don't count if you're not first.
這讓我愈加地恐懼
My fear grew.
恐懼對成績沒有好處  先生
Fear is not good for grades, sir.
于是我帶上更多的護符和戒指
I slipped on more charms and rings.
祈禱神的幫助  不  是祈求
Prayed to god for favors. No...begged for favors.
斷了16根骨頭  我卻有了2個月時間去反思
16 broken bones gave me two months to think and reflect.
最終  我醒悟了
Finaliy, sense dawned.
今天  我并不祈求這個工作
Today I didn't beg god for this job,
只是感謝老天給我的生命
just thanked him for this life.
如果你們拒絕我  我不會遺憾
If you reject me, no regrets.
我會繼續去完成生命中有意義的事
I'll still do something worthwhile with my life.
這樣的坦白對我們公司來說  并不是太好
Such frank behavior is not good for our firm.
我們需要的是  擅長與客戶打交道的人
We need someone diplomatic to handle clients.
你太直接了
You're too straightforward.
但是
But...
如果你能向我們保證  你會控制好態度
If you assure us you'll control this attitude,
或許可以考慮一下
we may consider you.
斷了兩條腿才讓我真正獨立
It took two broken legs to get me up on my feet.
好不容易有這種態度
Wasn't easy to get this attitude.
改變不了了  先生
Can't change it, sir.
你保留你的職位  我保留我的態度
You keep your job...I'll keep my attitude.
對不起  請別見怪
I'm sorry, no offense, sir.
等一下
Wait.
25年來  我面試了無數多的人
I've interviewed countiess candidates for 25 years.
每個人為了得到工作  都扮演成好好先生
Everyone turns into a yes-man to get the job.
你是從哪兒冒出來的  孩子
Where did you spring from, son?
先生?
Sir?
我們要談談工資嗎
Shall we discuss the salary?
太謝謝了
Thank you, sir.
我敬愛的陛下  您崇高偉大
Your majesty, thou art great.
請接受這謙卑的問候
Accept this humble offering.
戈爾文
Govind!
您說的  "如果他找到工作  就刮我胡子"
You had said, 'if he gets a job, shave it off.'
你做什么了
What have you done?
我感覺沒了胡子  就像沒穿衣服
I feel naked without my moustache.
我沒尊嚴了
I've lost my dignity.
我不會善罷甘休的  瑞絲奇
I won't accept defeat, Rastogi.
你過不了期末考試  就得不到工作
The job isn't yours until you pass your final exam.
這次由我來出卷子
And this time, I will set the question paper.
爸爸  那不公平
Dad, that's not fair.
愛情和戰爭中所有事都是公平的
Everything is fair in love and war.
這將是第三次...世界大戰
And this is world war...III
瑞絲奇  你死定了
Rastogi, you're dead meat!
你怎么來了
What're you doing here?
小心點
Be careful.
-你喝酒了  -就喝了一點
- You've been drinking. - Yup, had to down a couple.
喝得也太多了
A couple too many!
-需要一點膽量  -干什么
- Needed the guts. - For what?
-為了偷這個  -這是什么
- For stealing this. - What's this?
病毒辦公室的備用鑰匙
The duplicate key to Virus's office.
試卷被封在一個紅色封皮的袋子里
The question paper's in a cover with a red seal.
爸爸出的題目  為了讓拉賈掛科
Dad has set it, to fall Raju.
快去拿
Go get it!
你瘋了還是怎么了  那是作弊啊
Are you mad or what...that's cheating!
愛情和戰爭中所有事都是公平的
Everything's fair in love and war.
告訴我
Tell me something...
你真的認為
Do you really feel...
接吻的時候鼻子會碰一起嗎
The noses coilide while kissing?
來  吃點德卡拉 [鷹嘴豆蒸糕]
Wait. Have some Dhokla.
你們古加拉提人也太可愛了
You Gujaratis are so cute.
但為什么你們的食物聽起來這么嚇人
But why does your food sound so dangerous?
德卡拉  發達  漢瓦  色普拉  卡卡拉
Dhokla, Fafda, Handwa, Thepla, Khakhra
聽起來像導彈
Sound like missiles
來吧
C'mon
"今天布什向伊拉克投了2顆德卡拉"
'Today Bush dropped two Dhoklas on Iraq'
"造成400人死亡  200人受傷"
'400 dead, 200 injured'
來吧
C'mon
我能接受卡卡拉  發達  但你的名字...
I can deal with Khakhra, Fafda. But your name...
蘭柯霍達斯·沙瑪達斯·昌恰德
'Ranchhoddas Shamaldas Chanchad'
結婚后我才不愿意把我的姓換了
I won't change my last name after marriage.
琵雅  我們不能結婚
Pia, we can't get married
為什么
Why?
你還喜歡其他人嗎
Is there someone else?
沒有
No.
-你是同性戀?   -不是啦
- Are you gay? - No.
那你為什么不向我求婚
Then why don't you propose to me?
-難道你陽痿  -不是
- Are you impotent? - No.
那就證明給我看
Then prove it.
琵雅  別
Pia, no.
停  住手
Stop, stop!
-怎么了  -我們還沒告訴琵雅呢
- What happened? - We didn't inform Pia.
在這兒停下  我憋死了
Stop here, my bladders are bursting.
-閉嘴  -你還和她有聯系嗎
- Shut up! - Are you in touch with her?
沒有...我有她家的電話  在這兒停
No...I have her home number then call her, I'll stop.
這國家連撒尿的地方都沒有
No place for urine expulsion in this country.
-你好  請問琵雅在嗎  -不在
- Hello, is Pia there? - No, she's not.
那她在醫院嗎
Is she at the hospital?
為什么她要在那兒
Why would she be there?
她今天結婚  在馬納里
She's getting married today, in Manali.
太遲了  她結婚了
Too late! She's married.
還沒有  開車過去就6小時
Not yet. It's a six hour drive.
抓緊的話  我們能在宣誓前趕到
If we rush, we'll reach before the vows.
你覺得呢
What do you say?
還想什么  我們折回去
It's a no-brainer. Let's turn back
不許回去
No turning back.
直接去拉達克  等我們見了蘭柯后再回頭
Straight to Ladakh. We'll meet Rancho and return.
周五我和范素科·旺都還有個會議
I have a Friday meeting with Phunsukh Wangdu.
上車
Get into the car.
如果我錯過了會議  他就被日本鬼子搶了
If I miss my meeting, the Japanese will get him.
他們答應把他的名字加到公司名字中
They're offering him a first name in the company.
"范素科和藤良"公司  合資企業...
'Phunsukh and Fujiyoshi', profit sharing...
馬納里  255公里
琵雅和蘇哈斯的婚禮
-琵雅和蘇哈斯的婚禮  -這西裝  謝了
- Pia weds suhas! - Thanks for the suit.
病毒會犯心臟病的
Virus will have a heart attack.
在她每個女兒的婚禮上  我們都來搗亂
At every daughter's wedding, we're there to rock the party.
我去說服琵雅  你把那個金錢鬼引開
Listen, I'll update Pia, you peel off the price tag.
-法爾漢  -我們找到蘭柯了
- Farhan. - We found Rancho.
-給107房間的?  -是的  先生
- For Room 107? - Yes, sir.
-你動作也太慢了  -抱歉  先生
- You've taken ages. - Sorry, sir.
你走吧
Off, now.
-客房服務  先生  -進來吧
- Housekeeping, sir. - Come in.
愛啊  愛啊
Amore...amore...
快把我外套熨了
Quick, iron my coat.
愛啊  愛啊
Amore...amore...
找到蘭柯了  你不用嫁給這混蛋了
We found Rancho! Now you can't marry this ass.
你瘋了  法爾漢
You're mad, Farhan.
別騙自己了  琵雅  你還愛著蘭柯
Don't fool yourself, Pia. You still love Rancho.
你還在吃他最喜歡的東西
You're still eating his favorite food.
愛啊  愛啊
Amore...amore...
他無可救藥的  一日金錢鬼  終身金錢鬼
He's incorrigibie. Once a price tag, always a price tag.
別說了  法爾漢  蘇哈斯已經變了
Shut up, Farhan. Suhas is a changed man.
他不再開口閉口品牌和價格了
He doesn't speak of brands and prices anymore.
我15萬的外套啊
My 150,000 coat.
你們怎么這么愛吃薄荷醬
Why do you people eat sauce?
-我會搞定  先生  -怎么搞定
- I'll sort it out, sir - How?
我們干洗店專門清洗被薄荷色弄臟的衣服
Our laundry specializes in cleaning mint-stained suits.
我馬上就去弄干凈
I'll clean it in a jiffy.
快
Get it soon.
-太遲了  法爾漢  -琵雅
- But it's too late now, Farhan. - Pia.
到點了  琵雅  我們走吧
Let's go, Pia, we're late.
琵雅  是我  拉賈  別出聲  否則他們會殺了我的
Pia, it's me...Raju. Don't yell, they'll kill me.
蘇哈斯呢
Where is Suhas?
客房服務拿走了我的外套
Housekeeping took my coat.
去...把蘇哈斯給我弄過來
Go...send Suhas here.
現在離開儀式  太沒規矩了
It's rude to leave the ceremony.
-法爾漢?  -車準備好了
- Yeah, Farhan? - The car's ready.
抓住她的手就跑  別動
Grab her hand and run. Don't move.
-先生...  -我的外套呢
- Sir... - My coat?
你在這兒...
You're here...
-那在圣壇的是誰啊  -圣壇?
- So who's at the altar? - Altar?
再轉幾圈  我們就算結婚了
Another couple of rounds, and we'll be considered married.
我已經結過婚了  琵雅  我們走吧
I'm already married, Pia. Let's go.
太遲了  人們會笑話我的
It's too late. People will laugh at me.
那你就這么毀掉幸福?
So you'll commit suicide?
瑞絲奇
Rastogi!
他們也就傳言一段時間  馬上就會忘的
People will gossip briefly, then forget.
但是你...你會后悔死的
But you...you'll regret on your deathbed.
車就在門口  馬上就能和蘭柯一起
That the car was at the gate, Rancho within reach...
就因為怕這些人  你就嫁給這混蛋
But in fear of people, you married this ass.
你不是內個客房服務嗎
Housekeeping?
琵雅  還有個小問題
Pia, minor problem.
什么
What?
我們不知道蘭柯是不是結婚了
We don't know if Rancho's married.
什么
What!
-他不會結婚的  -那如果結了呢
- He won't be married. - And if he is?
那我們再送你回來
Then we'll drop you back.
放輕松  手工餅干吃嗎
Relax! Handmade biscuit?.
他怎么在這兒
What's he doing here?
別管他  這餅干很好吃的
Ignore him - the biscuit's very good.
到昨天為止  我都是個守法公民
Till yesterday, I was a law-abiding citizen.
但在過去的24小時  我迫降了一架飛機
But in the last 24 hours, I'd grounded an aircraft.
差點把某人的骨灰沖進下水道
Almost assigned Shamaldas's ashes to the sewers,
并讓一個新娘從自己的婚禮上逃婚
and made a bride elope from her own wedding!
全因為蘭柯
All for Rancho.
但他也一樣  會為朋友做任何事
But he too would do anything for friends.
例如從病毒的辦公室偷考卷
Like stealing the question paper...from the lion's den.
用紅色封印的信封
Envelope with the red seal.
他擔心如果拉賈沒考過  又會尋短見
He feared that if Raju failed, there'd be another high jump.
我們是有操守的賊  只為拉賈偷試卷
We were principled thieves, stealing the paper only for Raju.
我們發誓自己不會偷看一眼
We'd sworn we won't even take a peek.
藏在哪兒了...
Where's it hidden...
我們猴年馬月能找到啊  問問琵雅吧
We'll grow old searching! Ask Pia.
琵雅  你電話
Pia, your phone.
準父親大人
Mr. Papa-to-be,
如果你說"平安無事"  他就會踢一下
if you say 'all is well', he kicks.
他踢了
He kicked.
琵雅  你電話
Pia, your phone.
老爸辦公室
找到了  蘭柯
Found it! Rancho.
喂?
Hello?
快  復印一份
Quick, photocopy this.
原來放在哪兒的
Where was it?
放回去
Put it back.
-安全到達  -你們去哪兒了
- We're safe! - Where were you?
-給  -是什么
- Here. - What's this?
小意思
A gift.
考卷  病毒自己出的題專門要掛你
Question paper. Virus set it himself, to fail you.
奇怪啊  哥們
Strange buddies!
開始告訴你要正直
First teach you to be upright,
接著又給你一條通向可恥的道
then offer a path to shame.
不行
No way.
如果我過了  也是自己努力的結果
If I pass, it'll be on my own steam.
如果沒過  也沒什么
If I don't, it's still ok.
他把我倆說服了  我們像家人一樣緊緊相擁
He'd won us over! I felt like embracing him as a family...
但是接著我控制了下自己的感情
but then I controlled my emotions.
-該死的賊  -校長  求你了  校長
- Damn thief. - Sir, please, sir.
-騙子  -別這樣  校長
- Rascai. - Sorry sir.
想要改變教育制度
Wanted to change the system,
在我家門口撒尿
you'll pee on my door.
校長  您這是干什么呢
Sir, what're you doing?
住手啊  校長
Sorry sir.
你們被開除了
You are rusticated!
如果你們明天早上不離開  我就叫警察了
If all of you aren't out by morning, I'll call the police.
我會叫警察的
I will call the police!
騙子
Rascais!
一群騙子  你們都是
Rascais, all of you.
他怎么會有我辦公室的鑰匙
How did he get my office key?
我給他的  爸爸
I gave him the key, Dad.
我希望我能把這把鑰匙給我弟弟
I wish I'd given this key to my brother...
這樣他今天就還活著
he'd be alive today.
別說了  琵雅
Stop it, Pia.
你以為你兒子是掉下火車死的嗎
You think your son fell off a train and died?
閉嘴  琵雅
Shut up, Pia!
你決定讓他做個工程師
You decided he'd be an engineer.
你到底有沒有問過他想做什么
Did you ever ask him what he wanted to be?
你給了他那么大的壓力
You put such a pressure on him...
他選擇死亡來擺脫入學考試
that he chose death over the entrance exam.
我不明白...
I don't understand...
爸  你回房間去吧
Dad, you go to your room.
琵雅  別這么做
Pia, don't do this.
他想學文學  當個作家
He wanted to study literature, be a writer.
但他僅有的作品就是這封遺書
But all he wrote was this suicide note.
把那個收起來吧  求你了
Put that away, please.
別再粉飾太平了
No more cover-ups!
哪怕一次...
Just once...
你如果說  你不想就別學工程系
if you'd said - don't do engineering if you don't want to
就做你心里想做的
just do what your heart is in,
那么今天他就還活著
then he'd be alive today.
他不是自殺的
He didn't commit suicide.
你說得對  爸爸
You're right, Dad,
那不是自殺...
it wasn't suicide...
是謀殺
It was murder.
市區很多道路完全被水湮沒
Many city roads are completely submerged,
交通已經癱瘓
traffic has come to a standstill.
爸...
Dad...
莫娜  你怎么啦
Mona?
快回去  小個子  你跟著我們干嗎
Go back, Milimeter. Why're you following us?
干嗎  路又不是你家的
Why? Your pop owns the road?
請幫幫忙  我們現在走投無路了
Please help, we are desperate here!
你不能派救護車過來嗎
You can't send an ambulance?
從別家醫院調一輛車來
Get it from another hospital.
整個城市都遭水災了  我們無能為力啊
The entire city's flooded, sir. We're helpless.
莫娜  你還好嗎
Mona, you ok?
蘭柯  是琵雅
Rancho, Pia.
蘭柯  你們沒辦法來醫院了
Rancho, you can't reach here.
按我說的做
Do as I say.
羊水已經破了
The water bag has burst.
竟然通話結束  莫娜
Disconnected! Mona.
莫娜
Mona!
-打開燈  -放到哪兒
- Turn on the lights. - Where to?
桌上  乒乓球桌上
To the table, tennis table.
琵雅  我們到休息室了
Pia, we're in the common room.
拉賈  打開攝像頭
Raju, turn on the web camera.
莫娜呢  讓我看到她
Where's Mona? Show me.
稍等
Hold on.
這里  琵雅
Here, Pia.
姐姐  別怕  我在這兒呢
Mona, don't worry. I'm with you.
琵雅  我要死了
Pia, I'm dying!
蘭柯  就算沒有醫院和醫生
Rancho, even when there were no hospitals or docs
也可以接生
babies were delivered.
你們要一起把這個孩子生下來
You all will deliver this baby.
平安無事
All is well.
你們好大膽子  我要宰了你們
How dare you? I'll kill you.
爸  這事兒你別管了
Dad, stay out of this.
法爾漢  拿毛巾和剪刀
Farhan, get towels and scissors.
小個子  拿些布條和熱水
Millimeter, get clothes clips and hot water.
蘭柯  把莫娜蓋起來
Rancho, cover Mona.
姐姐  試著使勁
Mona, try pushing.
盡全力使勁
Push with all your might.
別嚎了  我不行啊
Stop it! I can't do it.
蘭柯  看看胎頭著冠了嗎
Rancho, check if there's crowning.
胎頭著冠...
Crowning...?
拿那個圖來
Get that diagram.
看看孩子頭露出來了沒有
See if the head is coming out.
快看看
Check quickly.
快去
Go!
去  蘭柯  去啊
Go, Rancho, go.
還沒著冠
No crowning.
莫娜  快使勁
Mona, please push.
莫娜
Mona!
她精疲力竭了  琵雅
She's tired, Pia.
叫醒她  如果她不使勁問題就大了
Wake her! If she won't push, it's a big problem.
-他們需要個真空吸盤  -他們上哪兒找去啊
- They need a vacuum cup. - Where will they get one?
真空吸盤是什么  怎么用呢
What's a vacuum cup? How is it used?
我演示給你看
I'll show you.
如果母親太累沒勁兒了
If the mother's too fatigued to push,
就把這個吸盤放在孩子頭上
a cup is placed on baby's head,
吸力把孩子頭吸住
suction makes the cup stick to the head...
接著把寶寶拉出來
and the baby is pulled out.
-我能做一個出來  -怎么做
- I can make this - How?
-用吸塵器  -吸塵器?
- With a vacuum cleaner - Vacuum cleaner?
對
Yes.
那個力道太大了
That pressure's too high.
-我能控制力道  -你有吸塵器嗎
- I'll control it. - Do you have a vacuum cleaner?
有  在我辦公室
Yes, in my office.
-法爾漢  趕緊去拿  -給你鑰匙
- Farhan, rush and get it. - Here's the key.
莫娜  使勁啊
Mona, push
天哪
Oh my God.
發生什么事了
What happened?
-拉賈  發生什么事了  -停電了
- Raju, what happened? - The power's gone.
那還怎么用吸塵器啊
How'll the vacuum work now?
法爾漢  你去拿吸塵器  我來搞定電源
Farhan, you get the vacuum, I'll get the power.
怎么搞定
How?
小個子  把病毒弄出去
Millimeter, get virus out.
這是干什么啊
What nonsense is this!
不是這個病毒  我的那個換流器啊
Not this virus. My virus, the inverter.
-去拿  快點  -好的
- Get that, quick. - Ok.
拉賈  把宿舍人都叫醒
Raju, wake up the hostel.
去拿所有車里的電池  電線  真空儀
Get car batteries, wires, and a vacuum gauge.
休息室有緊急情況
Emergency in the common room!
-蘭柯人呢  -在這兒呢
- Where's Rancho? - Here, sir.
把電池放這里  還有電線
Keep the batteries here...and the wires.
拉賈  關掉所有電源
Raju, switch off everything,
把換流器接到干線上
connect the inverter to the mains.
蘭柯  吸塵器來了
Rancho, vacuum cleaner.
法爾漢  把你的鏡頭清潔器拿來
Farhan, get your lens cleaner.
-吹球?  -對  拿來
- Blower? - Yeah, get it.
蘭柯  吹球
Rancho, blower.
好  把這個裝到計量器上
Good. Fix this to the gauge.
蘭柯  我這里搞定了
Rancho, I'm done.
-全關了嗎  -關了
- All switches off? - Yes.
把桌上的燈和電腦電源接通
Hit the table and computer switches.
好的
Ok.
拉賈  打開電腦
Raju, turn on the computer.
法爾漢  搬過來
Farhan, here.
琵雅  快過來
Pia, come here, quick.
愛死你了  蘭柯
Love you, Rancho.
-法爾漢  打開它  -好
- Farhan, turn it on. - Ok.
琵雅  用多大吸力
Pia, how much suction?
不大于0.5
Not more than 0.5.
-法爾漢  0.5  -蓋住它
- Farhan, 0.5. - Cover it.
0.5
吸塵器寶寶  太有才了你們
Vacuum cleaner baby! Mother of all deliveries.
法爾漢  可以了
Farhan, stop.
好的
Ok.
拉賈  到桌子上去
Raju, get on the table.
像這樣往下推寶寶
Push the baby down, like this.
好
Ok.
法爾漢  打開吸塵器
Farhan, turn it on.
加油  你可以的
Come on, you can do it.
加油  使勁啊
Come on, push.
為了你的小冠軍
Do it for Champ.
加油  莫娜
Come on, Mona.
他就要出來了
He's coming out!
你可以的
You can do it.
做得好  莫娜  使勁
Yes, Mona, push.
法爾漢  關了它
Farhan, turn it off.
好的  關掉了
Ok, off.
用兩個夾子夾住  剪短臍帶
Two clips, cut the umbilical cord.
法爾漢  在臍帶上夾兩個夾子
Farhan, two clips on the cord.
-拿剪刀  -小心點
- Get scissors. - Be careful.
從中間剪開  拿個毛巾來
Cut at the center, get a towel.
琵雅  孩子沒有哭啊
Pia, he's not crying.
小冠軍
Hey Champ!
蘭柯  按摩他的背
Rancho, rub his back.
-小冠軍  -加油啊  小冠軍
- Hey Champ. - Come on, Champ.
沒反應
No, nothing.
往他嘴里吹氣
Blow air into his mouth.
加油啊  小冠軍
Come on, Champ.
沒反應
No response.
莫娜  會平安無事的
Hush Mona, say "all is well".
他踢了一下
He kicked.
什么
What?
他踢了一下
He kicked.
說"平安無事"
Say "all is well".
平安無事
All is well.
如果病毒當時說一句"我孫子要做個工程師"
If Virus had said, "my grandson will be an engineer"
我會海扁他一頓
I would've broken his jaw.
但他最終說的那句話把我們大家都震住了
But when he finally spoke, he stunned us.
踢得好啊  想當個足球運動員嗎
What a kick! Wanna be a footballer?
做你想做的吧
Be what you want to be.
等等  我跟你還沒完呢
Wait. I've not finished with you!
大學第一天  你問了我一個問題...
First day of college, you'd asked me a question...
宇航員在太空為什么不用鉛筆
Why didn't astronauts use a pencil in space?
如果鉛筆尖斷了
If a pencil tip breaks,
它會因為沒有重力浮在空中
it'd float in zero gravity.
進入眼睛里  鼻子里  儀器里...
Get into eyes, nose, instruments...
所以你錯了
You were wrong.
你不能總是對的
You cannot be right all the time.
你明白嗎
You understand?
明白  校長
Yes, sir.
這是個很重要的發明
This was an important invention.
你知道嗎
You understand?
知道  校長
Yes, sir.
我的導師曾經說"當你遇到一個杰出的學生..."
My director said, 'when you find an extraordinary student...'
去吧  學習去  通過考試再離開
Go, study! Pass your exams and leave.
現在宣布年度學生獎...
And now, student of the year...
蘭柯霍達斯·沙瑪達斯·昌恰德
Ranchhoddas shamaldas chanchad
校長  一起合個影
Sir, one photo.
我想抓住所有這些瞬間  并把它們帶回家
I wanted to capture all these memories and take them home.
那天  我們擁抱  我們慶祝  我們哭泣...
That day, we hugged, we rejoiced, we cried...
我們發誓說每年大家最少相聚一次...
We vowed that we'd meet at least once a year...
誰料到  那竟是我們最后一次見蘭柯
Who knew then, we were seeing Rancho for the last time.
解開他
Untie him.
我要把你們全部告上美國法庭
I'll sue you all in an American court.
拉賈
Raju.
只有蘭柯才會辦一個這樣的學校
Only Rancho can create a school like this.
但他人在哪兒呢
But where is he?
別在這兒撒尿
Don't pee here.
走開  小東西
Go away creatures.
-別在這里撒尿  -不然我摑你
- Don't pee here. - I'll smack you.
這就對了  他肯定在附近
Bingo! He cannot be far.
請問一下  蘭柯霍達斯在哪兒
Excuse me, where is Ranchhoddas?
他不叫蘭柯霍達斯
He's not Ranchhoddas!
蘭柯...
Rancho...
徹侯特...見鬼  他到底叫什么
Chhote...dammit, what's his name?
冷靜一下  跟我來
Calm down. Come with me.
-他在哪兒  -蘭柯
- Where's he? - Rancho.
法爾漢  他讀過你所有的書
Farhan, he's read all your books.
拉賈  他每天都訪問你的博客
Raju, he reads your blog everyday.
還很驕傲地和孩子們分享
Proudly shares it with the kids.
還記得你的頭盔嗎  琵雅  它被盜了...
Remember your helmet, Pia? It was stolen...
你是誰  你怎么會認識我們
Who are you? How do you know us?
-你們都沒認出來我嗎  -沒有
- Didn't you recognize me? - No.
你怎么會呢  小個子都變大個子了
How would you? Millimeter is now centimeter.
不是大個子  都成男子漢了
Not centimeter, you're kilometer.
你怎么到這兒來了
How did you get here?
我收到了一封信  里面裝著火車票
I got a letter with a train ticket inside.
信里說"懷念學校嗎  搭這趟車"
It said  'Miss being in school? Catch this train'...
我就來了
I did.
那個騙子蘭柯
That rascal Rancho!
那個白癡在哪兒呢
Where is that idiot?
多吉  你來飛
Dorje, you fiy it.
每晚你都會出現在我的夢中
Every night you ride into my dreams,
騎著摩托而來  裝扮得宛如新娘
on a scooter, dressed as a bride.
取下的不是面紗  卻是頭盔
Instead of a veil, you lift your helmet.
信步走來  和我相吻
And come close to kiss me.
你走之前就不能跟我說一聲嗎
Couldn't you tell me before leaving?
不能
No.
對不起
Sorry.
你結婚了嗎
Did you marry?
什么  沒有
What? No.
-你呢  -差點兒就結了  白癡
- You? - Almost...idiot.
那么
So?
那么什么
So what?
你有愛的人嗎
Do you love someone?
有了
Yes.
誰
Who?
你啊
You.
看見了嗎  鼻子撞不到一起的  傻瓜
See, the noses don't collide, stupid.
是啊
That's right!
蘭柯
Rancho.
你好啊  法爾漢
Hi...Farhan!
好你妹
Screw your 'hi'.
-你聽我說...  -不  你聽我說
- Hey, listen to me... - No, you listen to me.
我可以解釋所有這些事情
I can explain everything.
你好  拉賈
Hi...Raju!
我們找你找得多辛苦
How we hunted for you!
你連打個電話的錢都沒有嗎
Didn't have a coin for one phone call?
把我那份兒也算進去
Add a couple from me too.
-騙子  混蛋  -饒了他吧
- Rascai, scoundrel. - Let him go now.
好  好  夠了
Ok ok, enough.
起來  快點
On your feet, come on.
玩得好嗎  白癡們
Having fun, idiots?
是查特啊
Hey...hi Chatur.
蘭柯霍達斯·昌恰德
Ranchhoddas Chanchad
你過得好嗎  老師先生
How do you do, Mr. Teacher?
你是個鄉村教師啊  蘋果的果  氣球的球
Wow, you're a teacher in a village, a for apple, b for ball...
我們的火車同時出發  你的卻倒著開回去了
Our trains left together. But yours traveied in reverse...
從工程師到小學老師
from engineer to primary teacher.
你工資多少  昌恰德  5000嗎
What's your salary, Chanchad? 5000?
我看來就像100美刀
For me that's $ 100.
我兒子的零花錢都比那個多
My son's pocket money is more than your salary.
-別說廢話了  -他告訴過我們的才是廢話
- Cut the crap. - Crap is what he gave us.
想要改變教育體系  改變世界
Wanted to change the education system, change the world.
到頭來他改變了什么  孩子的尿布而已
Finaliy what does he change? Kids' diapers.
是你去扁他還是我去
You gonna break his jaw or should I?
別激動
Just relax.
記得我說過有一天你會哭  我卻笑著嗎
Remember I'd said one day you'd cry and I'd laugh?
簽字吧  接受"你輸了  我贏了"
Sign here. Accept  "you lost, I won"!
"失敗宣言"  真不敢相信
'Declaration of defeat'! Unbelievable, man.
-查特  -瘋狂的家伙
- Chatur. - Crazy guy.
這是病毒那支筆啊  你怎么拿著它
Hey, this is virus's pen! You pinched it?
這你就別妄想了  伙計
Forget it, man.
這是給成功者的  不是失敗者
This is for winners, not losers.
萬一你學校周轉不開  給我助理打電話要捐款
If your school ever needs help, call my assistant for a donation.
蘋果的果  氣球的球...
A for apple, b for ball...
-他一點都沒變啊  -別管他了
- He hasn't changed at all! - Ignore him.
滿嘴垃圾
He's full of crap.
好消息是你的名字不是
Good news is your name
蘭柯霍達斯·昌恰德
isn't Ranchhoddas Chanchad.
想象一下  結婚之后我就是琵雅·昌恰德
Imagine, after marriage, I'm Pia Chanchad
惡心
Yuck!
那你真名叫什么
By the way, what is your real name?
范素科·旺都
Phunsukh Wangdu.
旺都?
Wangdu?
琵雅·旺都
Pia Wangdu!
你說你是個科學家?
You mean you're a scientist?
你有400項專利?
You have 400 patents?
我結婚后不想改名字
I won't change my name after marriage.
你就是查特說的旺都嗎
You mean you're Chatur's Wangdu?
你就是那個日本人都要討好的人嗎
It's you the Japanese are wooing?
我不喜歡旺都
I don't like Wangdu.
你是科學家還是老師呢
Are you a scientist or a teacher?
科學家  但我也教書
Scientist, but I also teach children.
這么說你就是那個范素科·旺都?
So you are the Phunsukh Wangdu?
對  對
Yes, yes!
-喂  消音器  -查特  回來
- Hey silencer. - Hey Chatur, come back.
吃屁吧
Take that.
等等  我有辦法讓他停下
Wait, I'll stop him.
范素科·旺都來電
旺都先生嗎
Mr. Wangdu,
真不敢相信你會打電話給我
I can't believe it's you.
對不起查特先生
I'm sorry, Mr. Chatur
我沒辦法和你公司簽約了
I can't sign the deal with your company.
怎么回事  先生  為什么呢  先生
What sir? Why sir?
我怎么簽啊  你把我的筆拿走了
How do I sign, man? You took my pen.
什么筆啊  先生  我沒明白你意思...
What pen, sir? I didn't get you...
你手里那個啊  病毒的筆
The one in your hand - Virus's pen.
旺都先生...
Mr. Wangdu...?
怎么啦  查特
Yes, Chatur?
蘋果的果  氣球的球...
A for apple, b for ball is...
搞砸的砸
...S for screwed.
你把我弄糊涂了  蘭柯
You got me, Rancho.
我是說旺都先生
I mean, Mr. Wangdu.
完全打敗我了  做得好
Totally floored me. Good one.
我希望我們個人問題不會影響這筆生意
I hope our personal problems won't affect this deal.
查特啊  接著這個
Hey Chatur, take that.
我剛才那是開玩笑的
I was just joking, man.
我深知你會大展宏圖
Deep down, I knew you'd do great things.
你坑爹呢
You're fibbing.
沒有  真的  我發誓
No, really, I swear.
蘭柯100分  查特0分
Rancho - 100, Chatur - 0.
你贏了  我輸了  你還不相信我嗎
You win, I lose. You don't believe me?
小心他要放屁
Beware of farts.
我敬愛的陛下  您崇高偉大  請接受這謙卑的問候
Your majesty, thou art great. Accept this humble offering.
免費建議  旺都先生
Free advice, Mr. Wangdu,
為了你的生活  跑吧
run for your life!
蘭柯  我會丟了工作的  我上有老下有小...
Rancho, I'll lose my job, man. I have small kids...
那個偉大的精神領袖蘭柯霍達斯曾說過
His holiness guru Ranchhoddas had correctly stated,
追求卓越  成功就會找上你
follow excellence...success will chase you, pants down.